Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chats. Okay, so let me just check if the chats are opened or not.
Krish NAik: Guys, please try to type in the charts. Yes, everyone? Good morning.
Krish NAik: Chaitan is telling not able to hear, but others are confirming that they can hear me. Chaitan, please have a check from your site.
Krish NAik: boil rate.
Krish NAik: I like to find you guys.
Krish NAik: So, let's talk about today's agenda.
Krish NAik: So, today's agenda will be the continuation of the last project. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Let me start sharing my screen, first of all.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think a few people have joined, let's…
Krish NAik: I was going through your community forum, so let me just open it.
Krish NAik: We don't need this stuff right now.
Krish NAik: Alright… Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, so yesterday, like, in the last class, a few people asked me about a complete stack with respect to AWS.
Krish NAik: Okay, so because of that, I shared a guest with you, like, if you guys are interested in that, you can have a look, okay? Like, in this course, I won't be doing that. After Project 3, I will be creating some teams, and people can start working on.
Krish NAik: That. Anybody has gone through the guests that I shared in the community forum?
Krish NAik: Okay, like, after project 3, that will be… because once you get to the basics of RAG, then, self-formation that I will be creating a team, and then you guys can start working. Okay, you can look into the guest. So, yesterday.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is… regarding course access, I think, it will be done from our end, okay? Don't worry. Because I think initially it's done from the back end, the team can take care of, okay? If Tanmai is here, Tanmai…
Krish NAik: Don't worry, okay? So, that particular extension will be taken from our site.
Krish NAik: Mohit is asking, where is Community Forum? This is the Community Forum, Mohit. I think everybody can see my screen.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's in your dashboard only, guys.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this particular concern, okay?
Krish NAik: Let me just recognize.
Krish NAik: Fine, then comes, okay, third…
Krish NAik: Alright, during the third project, I think, no. The third project will be a different one. I'm trying to, I'm planning hybrid rag with a self-healing architecture, okay? So that, Project 3 will be a bit different.
Krish NAik: So, with respect to self-filling architectures and RAG, integration of corrective RAG, okay, self-reflective RAG, those type of features I am planning.
Krish NAik: All right, now, okay, so Abhishek, I've been assigned to my organization to build an agent where four agents collaborate with two humans, do you think?
Krish NAik: Rather than creating custom agents from scratch, okay, try to use some frameworks, it makes your life easier.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you're a beginner, you can start always with Agno, Creve AI… okay, they are very, very easy for beginners.
Krish NAik: Once you're covered with the beginner level, then you can actually switch to line graph, about Ojin…
Krish NAik: Okay, Strand AI, so these are really good.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, Jakindar. Yesterday, only I came, so I responded.
Krish NAik: sessions on agents and multiple agents. Agents will be coming, so, like, once we have discussed the core part of the rack, then I'll be coming to the part in your syllabus. There is a dedicated agents module, so yes, we'll be talking about that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now another one…
Krish NAik: Alright, I think, there was another big one which was written, okay, I think this is the one.
Krish NAik: Prathamish told, I know Chris, so Academy deals with ML GenA overall, but to scale the application, we see SaaS apps care or about.
Krish NAik: Authorization, authentication, okay, auth tool, RPAC, API Gateway, Git, GitHub deployment.
Krish NAik: A few of the things we are discussing, but again, setting up those things, automated deployments like CICD pipelines, not a single branch.
Krish NAik: Those things can be done. Actually, dev staging plot, nobody teaches that from the AI perspective. Prathamish, if you are here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so all this will be taught from basics. Nobody will teach you from basics if you are in an AI-related course.
Krish NAik: Because, generally in MLOps, we used to teach, from basic distance, Pratamish.
Krish NAik: Such as Kafka, it can be Confluent, Kafka, Apache, Kafka, AWS, Kynas, so many different types of services, but again, that's not the priority in this course.
Krish NAik: how to make all of these applications become secure, scalable again. This is not related to this, because my main concern for any batch that we launch.
Krish NAik: My main focus will be towards AI part. With respect to streaming and other things, like, data engineering teams handle much more, so that's why that data engineering batch, you can look there specifically, we talk about from 3 cloud prospects.
Krish NAik: That might just sticking.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, major concerns are done.
Krish NAik: Now, Vijay's asking, are we going to have agents also in this course? Is agents less here? I don't know, guys. Do you guys check the syllabus before purchasing?
Krish NAik: Huh? How many directly purchased?
Krish NAik: Just because… We are offering things at affordable rates.
Krish NAik: language.
Krish NAik: Hmm…
Krish NAik: I think, live patches. Please go and check your syllabus, guys. You have a dedicated, like, if I go into your course, why it's telling you you are a guest? Even I don't know. Later on, I will check that part.
Krish NAik: In your syllabus, let me just show you what are the next flow that I'll be talking about.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that things become much clearer in the upcoming month.
Krish NAik: What we'll be talking.
Krish NAik: Okay, so after Haystack module that you have… okay, so after this module, we'll be talking about Langra. So Langara is for agents.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whoever has that thing that, we won't be talking about agents in this course, please at least check the syllabus.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we have a dedicated… see, in this course, I'll be talking about single framework. If somebody has, purchased previously, like, Agents 1.2 or 2.2, they are dedicatedly, we are talking about multiple frameworks.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's the only difference. I think probably Agent 3.0 will be coming around upgrade. In that case, you won't be going through, like, ragging depth. It will be much more agent-ic stuff there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please understand that in your course, you have agents.
Krish NAik: Alright, now,
Krish NAik: With respect to StructureTrag, also text-to-SQL part, we have gone through that, okay? So, let me tell you the next flow of the topics.
Krish NAik: So I think I can make this a bit bigger.
Krish NAik: Public.
Krish NAik: So, initially, this week, like, it will be the continuation of the project 2, same continuation, deployment, and then we will start with project 3, okay?
Krish NAik: No, no, no. Till now, like, graph rack, we have not discussed. SharePoint.
Krish NAik: Okay, so after Project 3, Project 3 will be, pretty much with…
Krish NAik: Hybrid, like, component is ready, I have to work on a little bit on that, cell-killing architecture that I am learning. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: hybrid RAG with, CGRAG plus
Krish NAik: SRAG, something like a combination of multiple things that I am planning to make the project. Okay, so we call it a self-healing architecture, so that will be your project three. Once we have completed project 3, then we'll be coming to haystar.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: After haystack, we will come to multimodal, pure multimodal.
Krish NAik: Okay, once multimodal is done, then we will start with our agent part, the liner off.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then we will come to… the agent input.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, your multimodal-based, once you have discussed, Project 4 will be based on multimodal. And finally, for your fifth one, like, till now, I have not finalized the project. I am planning…
Krish NAik: to build something like, if you know, like, open code or cloud code, but that project will take 2-3 months, so I'm planning, like.
Krish NAik: Little bit keeping it much more simpler, rather than going through.
Krish NAik: Okay, but from that, I want you guys to work with certain agents from your system level, because those type of projects goes on very, very long. So, like, initial fundamentals and everything that I will cover.
Krish NAik: Actually, how the agents interact with your operating systems, giving access to certain privileges.
Krish NAik: So, that becomes much tougher. So, that's why.
Krish NAik: Mithesh is asking, so is it safe to assume that the Landgrav agents in March? Yes, I think the last week of Feb or March, it will be around. So, that will be the last thing, and then I think, finally, that a very small module of MCP that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay, because again, now MCP is not trending so much, but 5 to 6 months back, it was pretty much trending.
Krish NAik: That will be fun, but that will… only that project might take 3-4 months, that's why.
Krish NAik: All right, now… okay, so this will be the main, overall flow. So, once we complete project 2, then we'll come to Project 3 directly, because you guys have already learned about hybrid RAG. Okay, so here, hybrid RAG with re-ranking, and a few certain other components, like corrective rag, self-reproductive rag, those things I'll be including in the same project.
Krish NAik: Then, one final, I can say, the framework for RAG, which is very famous, Haystack.
Krish NAik: Okay, there are so many other frameworks, like R2R is there, but again, I think probably in the next phase of our Rakuton Tour, those things I'll be including. But for now, according to the syllabus, these will be the major ones.
Krish NAik: UTCP, again, like,
Krish NAik: Universal commercial protocol is also coming through UCP from Google, so… These protocols comes, but again, standardizing them takes more than 2 to 3 years.
Krish NAik: So, it's very hard to say, okay, right now, this is good or this is bad. We don't judge in that.
Krish NAik: once it gets standardized, globalized, and probably some type of… I can say.
Krish NAik: one port number, we attach it, then properly I can say that it's a protocol.
Krish NAik: Till now, it's pretty much on-step, like SSH, one protocol.
Krish NAik: Telnet protocol. So, like, converting into a proper standardized, globalized protocol, it will take time 2 to 3 hours.
Krish NAik: Haystack land graph will be covered after project 3, correct.
Krish NAik: like Haystack, after Project 3, Langrav, I think in your course, you have a multimodal track, okay? So, after Project 4, we will come to Langrav. That will be the final one.
Krish NAik: I told you, like, Alpha Signal is there, majorly on LinkedIn, I do look into that.
Krish NAik: Would you include MCP, injecting documents from multiple sources? Like, Docklink has a dedicated MCP server through that you can use, but, again, like, in production, I never use MCP servers.
Krish NAik: Okay, Ambush, Sharma, anything.
Krish NAik: I don't use MCP servers in production. It's good for your learning initial phase, but actually in production using MCP,
Krish NAik: I don't feel like MCBs are very much secure. That's why.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this will be the core flow.
Krish NAik: No.
Krish NAik: Let's get back.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think a few services that we have in, pending state. The last class, I think 3 services, the SQL service.
Krish NAik: And then other few services that I have not discussed, we'll be going through that.
Krish NAik: Can you use RAG with MongoDB? MongoDB Web is a dedicated, like, vector DB. So, for sure, there you can do that.
Krish NAik: Mantas. Generally, like, people working with Mongo, like, NoSQL databases, they use the same vector DB from Mongo family of the…
Krish NAik: Alright, guys, so…
Krish NAik: Everybody, please open your text editor and get back to our TextualSQL rack project. It is the same repo, and the last class that we have discussed. We will now
Krish NAik: Do the continuation.
Krish NAik: Takshmi's asking, what do you use in production instead of using? I use proper modules.
Krish NAik: Once you guys have… once you guys are ready, please let me know in the chat, then we'll start with our discussion.
Krish NAik: That is around a budget, so I knew that first week of April, most of the things will be done. A rough estimation.
Krish NAik: Because I think the GenAI course will be coming around March.
Krish NAik: which Sunny will start, so by that time, the morning slot, that will go there. So, I think it will be done.
Krish NAik: Do we need to resend Git project again, resend? Do we need to resend? I didn't get data master anymore?
Krish NAik: Where were you only multi-data project AWS, where you were? Yes, that multi-data one only, but I have changed that report a whole. That's the only thing. I think two services are left, ones that we have discussed, and…
Krish NAik: In last class, I have shared the deployment document. Anybody has gone through that document?
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Can you give me details for the Gen AI project? Can you detail… give me details about the Gen AI project? Mitesh, I didn't get you, like, Gen AI project when you told.
Krish NAik: No, there will be some differences, Aniroth. Okay, so… I think probably, wait till second week of February, we will be getting that PDF.
Krish NAik: Can you send again the deployment? It's there in GitHub. You people have not looked into GitHub. Inside the docs, I shared one file, new underscore deploy.md.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have that document, it means that in the last class also, I told you I have already shared the document, the same steps that I'll be following.
Krish NAik: Because through EUI, it becomes very problematic for me that next, next, at every point of time, I have to show you. Rather than it will be pretty much CLI-based. So, all the steps and everything that is mentioned here.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, till now, it is not launched only Mitesh, so how can I share the link with you?
Krish NAik: Viraj, can you please cover how to deploy the project with open source embeddings model? You can simply change that embedding part, because right now, as I'm working with OpenAI embedding later on, you can switch to anything, Viraj. Because changing embedding models is not mine. Those things I know you guys can do.
Krish NAik: Because the main problem is if you are going ahead with an open source, in actual scenarios, you have to run it in some type of service.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that you have to force the embedding model.
Krish NAik: So, like, I generally use for hosting-related services, probably, like, Hugging Face or RunPod.
Krish NAik: Okay, but again, like, to teach those things.
Krish NAik: it becomes, because for run porting, you have to pay some money just to get that. Because, whenever I work with Quinn, 8 billion, those type of models, okay, you have to use a good intra, like, your VRAM should be, like, 28GB at least.
Krish NAik: So, you guys already know the MTV leaderboard. So, from MTV Leaderhood, you can do that. And Runport is the easiest one. Like, similarly, Hugging Face in one click, you can actually launch the entire infra.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, if you want, you can check that for notch.
Krish NAik: No, I have not made any tweaks, just for a final confirmation. Okay, so GitHub… Get repositories…
Krish NAik: Texas equal, can you say? Updated last week.
Krish NAik: This week, I was on vacation, so nothing. It's only last week the committee achieved.
Krish NAik: Small issue so far in S3 lifecycle JSON doc ID, okay, alright, chatting that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so guys, please provide me the final confirmation, and we start.
Krish NAik: Because, like, in the same notebook implementation of VANA, that will be true.
Krish NAik: No, no, it was India, the team was in Goa.
Krish NAik: we hired few people just to have a meetup. A lot of juniors are there. We are training them, so…
Krish NAik: It takes the time.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me start with, first of all, the VANA service.
Krish NAik: Wanna, one of…
Krish NAik: Australia only… one, perfect.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, this implementation is, exactly like your notebook implementation that I have taken. Okay, so you can refer to the same notebook, I think there is a notebooks folder, and if you remember, this notebook I have already discussed in the class.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now the same implementation is here, but rather than I have wrapped it inside a function.
Krish NAik: Adapted inside a class, everything.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, a few common imports.
Krish NAik: Then comes, our logging service with respect to our SQL. Okay, so I'm initializing the logger. Then comes… now, these are the
Krish NAik: main imports with respect to VANA that I'm taking. So, first of all, like, this is VANA 2.0 that we are working with from VANA import agent. Integrations, OpenAI, so I'll be working with the OpenAI LLM service.
Krish NAik: Then comes from VANA Integrations, the PostgreSQL runner. Okay, now it totally depends upon your database selection. I hope everybody remembers, VANA supports a different type of database. Snowflake integration is there, EWS, and others are available.
Krish NAik: Then comes Tool Registry. Okay, through Tool Registry, the, available tools inside VANA will be accessing them. And finally comes your RunSQL tool. This is the actual tool that, we will be using for,
Krish NAik: RunSQL tool does the execution for any type of SQL query that has been generated by your natural, LL.
Krish NAik: Then comes user resolver, user and request context. So whenever we are making a call, first of all, we have to wrap it through our request context.
Krish NAik: Now, Pinecone integration for agent memory. So, one is this default one. So, if you remember, I had created two indexes. Okay, so let me just show you.
Krish NAik: Because I have not covered that, SQL training path.
Krish NAik: Till no. Later on, I'll be doing it. Once I complete this part, let me just log into the service.
Krish NAik: Mithesh, that is, possibly Lama Index.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: not here.
Krish NAik: We're selecting few tables.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this VANA SQL training, if you, look into this one. Okay, so this one I created because I was planning to show you how SQL training is done. Okay, but, that module till now I have not discussed. So once the project is done, that I will be discussing in the first step only.
Krish NAik: Because by providing few examples, example pairs when I'm talking about, it means that your query, with that query, what will be the generated output. Okay, so for every user query, you'll be writing, you know, this is the actual SQL.
Krish NAik: So, those we call golden examples. So, through those golden examples, we train it. So, you need a lot of examples. So, really, you have to create that set by yourself.
Krish NAik: Because when I'll be showing, I'll be showing very few examples, but actually, in real world, you need more and more examples.
Krish NAik: Okay, just like evaluation set, whenever you are evaluating any RAG, you have to create the evaluation set by yourself. A very similar example. The more examples you keep it, I will say, the better results that you get from one.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, we can use this demo agent memory. Okay, so this is the default one.
Krish NAik: Just for, local…
Krish NAik: purpose, but for persisted memory, using specific vector indexes with Pinecone or with any VectorDB that you can do at.
Krish NAik: Then, I am importing a few of the settings. If you remember, with respect to VANA, I have very specific settings here.
Krish NAik: I think these are a few of the main, configurations of VANA, okay? So now, these… one is the VANA model, so exactly which
Krish NAik: OpenAI model that I'll be working with for training, what type of indexes, the VANA SQL training. The namespace, for now, I've given a SQL agent. Okay, now this will be the namespace, which will be used by Pinecone.
Krish NAik: Then comes your VANA temperature. Now, these things I have kept for a deterministic output. Previously,
Krish NAik: as I was testing, okay, the default settings of one are not deterministic, so that's why I've kept it, deterministic as well, so that any point of time, if you re-execute the same query, you will get the same output.
Krish NAik: So, these are all the SQL LLM configuration. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, these will be used in your SQL, so that's why our from app input settings.
Krish NAik: Now, comes your class, a simple user resolver. Okay, now this is where I have actually, defined my user. So, you can provide user, if you remember, even in our previous notebook, I created a user, like, example
Krish NAik: admin at the right example.com, you can keep them in groups. Okay, so this is much more with respect to access controls, I can see.
Krish NAik: Now, our main execution with respect to the agent that we'll be doing. So, class, the VANA agent wrapper, then comes the main initialization. Here, I'll be passing all my
Krish NAik: global LLM settings. So, your OpenAI key, what is the database URL? Okay, the Pinecone API key. So, first of all, the initialization of the LLM.
Krish NAik: From OpenAI, as I'm working with.
Krish NAik: Then, a few… just to show the logging info, that's why I've kept it. Now, these things are imported from the settings screen that I have, your config.py.
Krish NAik: Now, A is asking, what is the use of VANA? I have taken a dedicated class for VANA, please check. It's used widely for text-to-SQL tasks.
Krish NAik: Now, I have defined a payload. Now, this particular payload is,
Krish NAik: actually for getting your deterministic output. So, all the settings that I'll be passing for the LLM, that's why I've defined that particular payload. So, this payload is responsible to… through deterministic output, and I'll be passing all these parameters that I have defined from my settings.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this payload, I will be updating, as you can see, deterministic build payload data. Now, this particular function is through which I'm passing all the settings, and I'll be making the SQL LLM call just to generate my natural language to SQL task.
Krish NAik: Okay, because firing a query, once you will have the query, you can fire it directly using any type of tool, like your, any type of, like, the driver which comes, the Postgres driver. If you install that, you can directly delete out that query, or you can use the RunSQL tool from VANA also.
Krish NAik: If you don't use this, just remember that what will happen
Krish NAik: If you don't use a deterministic.
Krish NAik: LLM, then what will happen, guys?
Krish NAik: quickly tell me in the chat. It's common…
Krish NAik: It's not like it's unique in VANA, it's common to any LL.
Krish NAik: it means that your output will change. The default parameter of VANA, it goes, like, 0.3 to 0.7. Here, I don't want any creativity, because if the same call is making… see, you have to think about
Krish NAik: If my catcher, okay, because if I know that I'll be using the catcher for sure. Now, in that catch, if something that comes in the same step, I'll be directly picking it up from the catcher, and I'll be sure. Because you know that we have the request and the response, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no. So that's why, like, I thought about why to change this, rather than keep it deterministic. At every point of time, making a creativity here doesn't make sense.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, you have to think, because if the same query comes into the picture, we know that we'll be picking it from catcher. If something doesn't come from there, then again, I'll be making the call.
Krish NAik: Alright, and now this implementation I did actually before the catch-up part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, later on I implemented Kachi, but I know that this should be in anyone's case. You should always go with the deterministic output.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, explainability of your solution becomes much more harder.
Krish NAik: Anituto asking, are you using static catcher? Yes, our catcher is pretty much static only.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, alright, now through payload, as you can see, this entire function that I'm calling it the deterministic build payload. Now, here, my Postgres runner. Okay, where I'll be passing my database URL, so this is the initialization to your Postgres service.
Krish NAik: Then, I'm, I will be creating a tool, okay, the RunSQL tool, that needs to be initialized from the tool registry. First of all, created an object, and through that, I am accessing. And here I am passing, okay, now this tool can be used by these main access groups.
Krish NAik: Now, previously, I've already defined the user resolver. From there, I've just created a simple object. Through that object, I'll be accessing it.
Krish NAik: Now, initializing the agent memory, so two types of memory, so if you have the Pinecone memory, it's fine, otherwise we'll be using the demo agent memory. So, by default, demo agent is always good, but again, remember, the data won't be persistent here. So, that's why we have a dedicated pincone index format.
Krish NAik: Then, now… now this initialization is exactly… because this thing directly, I've copy-pasted it from the notebook only. Okay, so here…
Krish NAik: This is the main VANA agent initialization, where I'm passing my LLM, the tool, the user resolver, and the agent memory.
Krish NAik: Now, inside my VANA agent wrapper, I have a dedicated function, generate SQL async, because in VANA 2.0, everything is async. Okay, so that's why I've just given the name, otherwise…
Krish NAik: I made the function async, and then I was actually getting an error, so everything here will be pretty much asynchronous tasks.
Krish NAik: Now, this particular function takes what? It will take a question.
Krish NAik: And what? The schema context.
Krish NAik: Okay, two things. Generate sequel. Now, this is the main one, okay?
Krish NAik: Like, you will pass any type of natural language, it will go to the LLM, and based on that, it will be generating the SQL.
Krish NAik: Now, if schema context is equal to true, full message schema context with the quotient that will be passed, else only the quotient. Now, you know that without the schema context, it might say correct.
Krish NAik: So, like, I feel that, you should always pass the schema context. In the notebook, I showed you that without the schema context also, you might get correct answer, but if your schema is really complex, it's better to keep it as a context and pass it to the
Krish NAik: Now, extracting SQL from the agent. Now, this is where… this is the return type through which I'm actually passing this, you know. Now, this is another one that I have, that I'll be calling it.
Krish NAik: Do you have a schema for Mongo collections? No, not for… here, Mongo collections I don't have, so for sure, I don't have that Mantage.
Krish NAik: Now, extract SQL from the main agent. Now, what is the purpose of this?
Krish NAik: extract SQL from the agent. How many of you remember the response type of VANA?
Krish NAik: There were multiple components. How many of you remembered that?
Krish NAik: from multiple components, I have to do the extraction of that SQL, Anybody remembers?
Krish NAik: Huh? Please tell me.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, if you don't remember, you have to look into the notebook. There were really a lot of components that were thrown. Now, from those components, you really need to look into that. So, please look into this notebook before, directly, if somebody
Krish NAik: here is new, it's better to get into that first. So, first, look here, and I think
Krish NAik: Yes, can you see? So many components are there.
Krish NAik: out of these components, we have to do that extraction, or simple parsing. Okay, so many rich components are there, so you have to actually look into the output. So, for example, if you see here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so sum here, your result will be there.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I asked the question, like, there are 100 customers. Okay, now you can see the answer is also there. So, similarly, you'll be having the SQL, so you need to do the extraction one.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, first of all, initializing our request context. Okay, and what are the different types of header, cookies, remote address, all those things that I have passed it.
Krish NAik: Now, this is our main block. So, from components, self-assense, send message. Now, this is the part where I'm actually extracting. I'm looking for whether it has the attributes which has been returned by the SQL agent, and from there, I'm extracting the data.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because, really, the return type is really long, and from one by one. These are all UI-based components, and from those components, you have to extract that particular data.
Krish NAik: And the same thing I have done in the notebook also, if you remember.
Krish NAik: If you see, this is the same piece of code, guys. It's not like that I have done anything new. It's the same implementation from the notebook that I have taken.
Krish NAik: And here, if you remember, even we had a field of explanation. How many of you remember? Like, when the SQL is generated, with that, even you will be getting the explanation from your agent.
Krish NAik: Okay? So that particular component also needs to be extracted if you feel that, yes, you need that explanation. Why?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, if, not the condition that comes, the agent did not generate the SQL, please try refacing your question, this will come.
Krish NAik: Then comes def… your SQL… this is the SQL execution part.
Krish NAik: Okay, and directly here, execute and extract results that I'm actually calling this particular function, return type.
Krish NAik: Okay, now below, I'll be having the entire context. Now, here, a simple condition, execute and extract results. Okay, sometimes what happens in your return type, if the VANA doesn't respond, in that case, I have taken this entire, logic that, okay, if the run SQL tool fails the entirety, you can use the
Krish NAik: driver.
Krish NAik: Because if you have the SQL with you, do you think that you need Vana to do the execution? Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Can you execute it directly using a Postgres driver?
Krish NAik: That's a simple logic. It means that you can execute the SQL query
Krish NAik: using VANA, or directly using Postgres driver also, you can do it. Okay, so that's why I've kept it in this particular condition.
Krish NAik: Alright, first off…
Krish NAik: Well, a very similar condition through the driver, I'm connecting to my Postgres, and you can say, on.cursor, I'm executing the SQL. Okay, so that is the main thing, so it's a pretty much fallback, because sometimes I failed that the run SQL agent, I was getting some type of issues and that, so I've kept a fallback to the original drive.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, finally, the SQL query that you have executed. From there, it will be getting the results.
Krish NAik: Now, this is my main text-to-SQL service. Okay, now inside this service, I'll be keeping all those things that I have defined above.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much now, that query catcher service previously, that I have defined, this particular service, now this particular… because till now, we have not kept anything with respect to the catcher, but right now, those catchy implementations, that will also come.
Krish NAik: So, a few conditions with respect to your common configurations, the database URL, then you have the OpenAI API key, whether you have the query catcher service, which is pretty much optional, then coming to some type of validations, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, this is my main VANA agent wrapper class that I have created.
Krish NAik: Because all those functions that I told you, this was part of this particular class, okay?
Krish NAik: So, created a simple object vana for our main class, I hope everybody remembers.
Krish NAik: This is the actual class that we have created, through which, okay, now I'm, now the idea is to use all those functions, okay, within your class. So, simply I've created an object, and through that particular object, I'll be accessing it.
Krish NAik: So, alright, this is the MEM settings.
Krish NAik: Now, here, this part is new. Everybody please focus here, because till now, I have not taught you the VANA training, the VANA, traditional training with golden examples.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this part is a little bit new.
Krish NAik: So, please, everybody, focus on this part. So, first of all, the object part came.
Krish NAik: Then comes operable workflow state, like self.pending queries. How many of you remember that, we took a Boolean value, okay, for the execution of the SQL with a true and false condition?
Krish NAik: By default, we're told that none of the SQL queries only be executed. But if you meet that Boolean.
Krish NAik: true, then only the SQL execution will take place.
Krish NAik: Okay, because it's a bad practice to, give the access to anyone, that every user can fire the query.
Krish NAik: Okay, there should be limited group of users who can do that, so that's why that approval state was there. Okay, and once you have that pending query, you will get a unique ID for that particular query, and using that unique ID, you can do the SQL execution. I hope everybody remembers that in our workflow.
Krish NAik: Yes, the approval section, correct, Balaji.
Krish NAik: Nobody remembers?
Krish NAik: This is for the router to select SQL, no honey root. Router service is this one. This is where I actually, like.
Krish NAik: I was taking the approval. In my case, I told that directly you should not do the firing of your query on top of the DB. You should have limited access. That's why that approval. So I generated a unique string for every query.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why that particular… because I know that I have discussed this previously when I showed you through the URL.
Krish NAik: So, the main idea was that SQL execution should not be done by everyone. Generation can be done, okay, by everyone, there is no problem, but the execution part should be done by limited.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, self, is trained, because right now, we have not done any training, so that's why this particular flag is false. Then comes our self.schema context, okay? So, right here, later on below, you will see that a very big schema context that I have provided.
Krish NAik: Now, dev, complete training. So, right now, really, I'm not done any training here.
Krish NAik: So, this part I'll be discussing later on, because I don't have… I've not created any golden examples also. So, for that, you need to create your own, I can say, example pairs. Like, your actual query, based on that query, what will be the, SQL output from the LLM.
Krish NAik: Now, coming to, building the schema context, okay, now this is the main
Krish NAik: database overview that I have, okay? So here, as you can see, so first of all, coming to the main documentation of the database, what are the important tables that I have? The e-commerce database, important notes, table customers columns, so pretty much a big one.
Krish NAik: directly from the notebook, their same implementation that I have, we have picked it.
Krish NAik: Devati Sissai is telling you? Is this human in the loop? No. This is nothing from human in the loop.
Krish NAik: Okay? It's simple schema context. It means that the schema about our database, that information that I have kept it here.
Krish NAik: Okay, your human in the loop will come when I will be discussing agents.
Krish NAik: I'm not discussing, guys.
Krish NAik: Now, see, here, these are a few golden examples, because, see, really creating a set for that I have not done, but I have provided few examples here, so that you guys at least can understand, like, how your dataset will look like when you actually do a training.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is, like, how many customers do I have? Now, for that, what will be the exact sequel? I hope everybody gets it. When you create your own set.
Krish NAik: Okay, because for your database, it's a very good practice that you'll be creating the set by yourself.
Krish NAik: Then it becomes much more easier.
Krish NAik: Yes, in the real-world project, you might have 10,000 tables, then also.
Krish NAik: the same thing that takes place. Because if, the first thing… it becomes much easier for the LLM to understand your schema.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And you should always provide with better examples. Then it becomes much more easier with respect to the algorithm for your database.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, same. Any LLM knows this equal.
Krish NAik: But generating the query, sometimes, if you're actually working with much more complex queries, I have seen that it fails. So that's why the option is there in VANA to actually train. Because according to your database, you might know that, okay.
Krish NAik: I can say 50% of the queries you can, like, predict, but rest 50% totally upon the users. It might… might… they can ask anything. Later on, those things which will be asked for the user, it will be part of your drill.
Krish NAik: It means that this trend set will increase with… in time, in future. Because all those queries, you can keep it. In that way, you'll be making your system better. Initially, it won't be very much good. Once more queries are coming, then you can actually add them into your actual set.
Krish NAik: Yes, somehow, through, context compression theory, you have to do that.
Krish NAik: All right. Shanket is asking, is this training R of the VANA agent exactly correct?
Krish NAik: Alright, so…
Krish NAik: Now, the entire context that I have kept it here in one shot. Then comes general. Now, this is the function, it's only for my purpose, okay? Generate SQL for approval, okay?
Krish NAik: And here, a few implementations with respect to the catcher part, because if the same thing that comes from the catcher, it will be picked up. Otherwise, simply, it will go to the main VANA agent for the entire execution.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if not self-strained, now this is the part with respect to an exception that I have kept it. So that's why the SQL training part I'll be showing you in the same notebook I will create after I've completed the project. It will be better for your understanding.
Krish NAik: Because that's why Vana is widely adopted in production.
Krish NAik: only for, generating, from natural language to SQL.
Krish NAik: Now, here also, we'll be checking the catcher if self.queryCatcherService, okay, and self.catcher enabled, then directly we'll be looking for the main key, the actual portion that I have.
Krish NAik: And from there, you can actually look into the result. Now, how many of you remember catchy type is equal to SQL underscore J? What is this?
Krish NAik: What else does quickly tell me? In the last class, I have discussed.
Krish NAik: What is this SQL underscore gen?
Krish NAik: SQL query catcher, so… Cache, everybody is stealing catch, ketchy, catchy, but exactly. The key, guys.
Krish NAik: In the last class, I told you I have dedicated how many keys?
Krish NAik: In my query catcher purpose.
Krish NAik: 4 keys, okay, 2 keys were for our RAG, okay, and two keys were for our SQL agent.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why that particular key, I'm looking into that.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Now, if catcher result and SQLint catcher result, logger.info, SQL generation, catch a hit. So from here, directly in the response, the catch hit condition will be pretty much true.
Krish NAik: Now comes the query IT generation for the approval workflow for every workflow, so that's why I've kept it
Krish NAik: If you remember, whenever the SQL will be generated, that, directly I won't be doing the execution. Through query ID, I can access those generated SQLs later on, which I can execute it.
Krish NAik: And I'm, saving all those pending queries right now, within, the list, like, all the queries
Krish NAik: whichever has been generated. First of all, they will be coming to the pending query, and then one by one, you'll be doing the execution of it.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, this is the state.
Krish NAik: Now, if, we are directly getting the result, okay, so… now, this is the other written type that I have for this particular function, the main one.
Krish NAik: So, return the query ID, the quotient, the SQL. Now, this is the actual API response type that I am using for this particular one. Now, this particular value, it's just not a correct one, because if you change the model based on that,
Krish NAik: I have not built any cost tracking module. Okay, so simple random values that I have kept it. But,
Krish NAik: When you are actually doing an implementation, you need a proper cost tracking module for every LLM.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, if you look here, what are the things that I'm returning? One is basically your catch-it result, then come your catch-it explanation, because in my
Krish NAik: SQL output, I was throwing both the things, the natural language to the SQL that got generated, as well as the explanation for that SQL, while it was generated.
Krish NAik: By default, the status will be pending approval, so this is the default state. Okay, and in this condition, as we are picking it from the catcher, the catch rate condition will be true.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, in the next step, that comes…
Krish NAik: Okay, so comes our generating the SQL using VANA 2.0 agent directly. Now, if something is not there in the catcher, it means that we'll be generating it, and we'll be putting that in the catcher, so that is the next step, cache, the SQL generation result. Okay, if it doesn't fall in the catcher, you have to put it in the catcher, yes or no.
Krish NAik: If something is not available in the catcher, so for every user query, you'll be putting it into the catcher? No, now that particular logic will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, that's why I'm initializing my main VANA agent, and from here, generate SQL async. This is the main one, because through this, I can generate
Krish NAik: the actual SQL which is required to fire on top of your Postgres database.
Krish NAik: Now, if it is not available, so these things will be put in directly on top of the catch, and what are the things that I'm catching? The SQL, the explanation, and the question. Because I think these three things are sufficient.
Krish NAik: Here's funny.
Krish NAik: Because if you are catching these values, you have a pretty much good idea. The actual SQL, the explanation, and the actual question, basically the query.
Krish NAik: Now, here, the TTL that I have kept it is only 24 hours.
Krish NAik: Sanket is asking, so are these catches for every user?
Krish NAik: No, no, see, I have not implemented user-level catcher. It's the global one for every user that will come.
Krish NAik: It's a global one, Sanjay, not user-specific.
Krish NAik: All right, now, this is the catch time to leave detail. By default, in my settings, I have kept it 24, I can say.
Krish NAik: Now, Rajat is selling, what'll booster?
Krish NAik: What is booster in SQL query that is being generated?
Krish NAik: What is Booster? Rajata will look into that. Okay.
Krish NAik: First of all, okay, I'm saving all those catches services if they are not available. Again, like, generating a unique ID for the approval workflow, because in this case, yes, once you have saved everything.
Krish NAik: But again, your natural language that has been generated for that execution, again, I'll be putting them into the pending query state. Okay? So that's why, again, the return type. Then comes execute approved query. So once your query is approved for that particular query ID,
Krish NAik: Okay? Then, in the next step, I'll be executing. Now, for that particular SQL execution. I am accessing one by one, the query ID from our main list, okay?
Krish NAik: And this is the actual, like, this is the return type, the query ID status rejected, because there you have to pass the Boolean of true and false, query execution canceled by the user. That's why I kept it.
Krish NAik: And finally, like, check if this is a query, like, this is a simple cleaning of the string just to check that everything is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: Because select will come, yes or no. Any SQL query will come with select or not, please tell me.
Krish NAik: Because the SQL that will be generated by the LLM, in that case, I have kept this particular condition just as a verification.
Krish NAik: Check the catcher for the selected queries. If the query is available in the catcher, then again, you'll be picking it up from the catcher.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, right now, Monmouth, you have to think about, I'm not talking about much more complex, but in simple level, when you are doing, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, if you want more and more conditions, you can add a specific function, and you can actually call that function through that for any type of, the generated SQL verification.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, the catcher check is done, and finally, whatever the result from the catcher get will be picked up, it will be thrown.
Krish NAik: If that particular condition fails, then again, the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so execute the SQL using the VANA2.agent. Now, I told you, there, you have the specific run SQL tool in VANA. Through that, you can do the execution, okay? And the same thing, like, once it is approved, you can do that, or using your Postgres driver also, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Now, I had a very dedicated route, just to show you the pending queries, and now this is where dev get pending queries that I have. Okay, this will list all the pending queries, okay, which are waiting for approval.
Krish NAik: Alright? Now, I think this is the core VANA service. Okay, now, more and more, I can say, features that I can add it, but this is a rough, high-level intuition of a text-to-SQL service that you can keep.
Krish NAik: Because, as you know that, in my case, I have taken a dummy data based on that. Now, more logic things will come if your state is much more complex, for sure.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: the SQL service.
Krish NAik: is done.
Krish NAik: Okay. Then comes… which other services are remaining? Because in the last class, vector service was done, storage backend was done, SQL was done, S3 was done. Okay, RAG service was also done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think this service that I am remaining, the query capture service, okay? Okay, and the router, alright, these two services are remaining.
Krish NAik: Fine, let's talk about the query catcher service.
Krish NAik: Now, query catcher service is for what type of task, guys? Quickly let me know.
Krish NAik: Routing is the final thing that I'll be talking. Yes, after this, I will come to the router service.
Krish NAik: Yes? What is the purpose of this query catcher service?
Krish NAik: Because for this, I'm using Redis, okay? And in Redis, what I was saving? Four things. The RAG, query response, similarly for the SQL agent, query response, okay?
Krish NAik: That's why. Reddish. For other things, I actually kept it in S3.
Krish NAik: for dock catching service, so that's why this name service is the query catcher. There, you have the docking catcher, the document label catcher.
Krish NAik: Or late.
Krish NAik: So first of all, here, import JSON, hashlib, okay, because, unique hashes that I'll be generating for my caches, then comes import logging, from typing, date time, okay, so a few pretty common imports, initializing my logger, okay? And now.
Krish NAik: the radius catcher service for our query results, embedding, and SQL, everything that I'll be saving it.
Krish NAik: Now, see, whenever you are doing, because somebody asked the question, like,
Krish NAik: if you're actually generating the embeddings, everything, can I say that
Krish NAik: it will come, that you will be charged. It doesn't matter whether you are using open source, or…
Krish NAik: Paid. Because in production, open source means that you have to host that service somewhere, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because embedding… see, embedding is such type of task that I feel that it won't be running continuous.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally two types of embedding service that we do. One, that can be serverless. It means that on basis requirement, you switch on the service, probably in some EC2, or as some type of dedicated cluster that you can keep it as AWS Lambda also, because
Krish NAik: I feel that embeddings, two types. One is that query embedding. That query embedding, that comes, no, you have to run the service always.
Krish NAik: Okay, because every user, just think about if your system is active, like, 24 hours, everybody's working. In that case, you need that.
Krish NAik: But if you feel that for your document level, okay.
Krish NAik: document-level embedding. That means that when you upload a document into the system, chunking is done, then embedding. Now, that particular service, you can keep it as a serverless.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, the query one, it's not required that you keep it as a serverless. That's why I'm telling you this, particular, logic that, okay, so generally, we keep both the things, whichever, because, for embeddings, if I use something much more complex.
Krish NAik: like, Quinn-based models or something. Then for document label, I can actually use a serverless
Krish NAik: But for query, you need something which is continuously running.
Krish NAik: Because most of the times, I know, if it's an active system, it's not very active. Sometimes during a day, then serverless is also fine.
Krish NAik: So, always decide that architecture based on the, like,
Krish NAik: generally, I look into the Dow amount, okay, a few certain things, monthly active users, daily active users, from there, I overall get an idea what are the peak hours. Okay, so from that, those numbers, it actually helped me to derive
Krish NAik: my optimization level, till what point I can optimize my current system.
Krish NAik: Sankyat is asking, most of the time, people host embedding service or use it from providers like Bedroom.
Krish NAik: You can use it in Bedrock, but I prefer, like, both the things. Like, it means that Bedrock, or in Bedrock, you don't have everything.
Krish NAik: In AWS, in Marketplace, Sankit, you can do a connection, and that billing of those embeddings can come to your main AWS account.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can host your Unos, like, through Hugging Face or through RunPot.
Krish NAik: Those are widely used.
Krish NAik: Now, generally, like, if you're working with, very…
Krish NAik: pick, like, an 8 billion model where you need a GPU of at least 20GB RAM, then generally I don't use AWS. I generally go with serverless GPUs. It becomes much more cheaper for me, something. I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: In Bedrock, you can use, you have Titan, you have Voyage in Marketplace, everything is there in the Marketplace of AWS.
Krish NAik: We track this down now.
Krish NAik: Every product, anybody is building SOHAM. Everybody tracked down.
Krish NAik: Daily user activity, monthly user activity, these things are very much common in any product that you are building.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, how the business teams will take any decision?
Krish NAik: It's very, very important down.
Krish NAik: Later on, Ravi, I will be coming to semantic catcher, okay, assuming, we can run it as a cube, nodes and scale. Yes, Kubernetes-based, if you, keep it as a dedicated port, okay, which is continuously running, and on demand, it can scale up easily, correct, Muhammad?
Krish NAik: Josephina asking, meaning by two different services used for embedding, like, server and serverless? Yes, that's the main idea. Because generally, the query service, I don't put a lot of load in it. While for your document embedding services, Josephine, there will be more load on that.
Krish NAik: Because one pushed 100 documents. I know that that is a much more, computationally heavy operation.
Krish NAik: As compared to processing a single query, Joseph. I hope you get that. That's why it's a good practice to keep both the services as a separate
Krish NAik: which tool? I use OpenCode, which GLM?
Krish NAik: Even, Codex also I use. I use so many tools, like Kira. There are no limitations on that.
Krish NAik: Okay, Josephine, server and serverless, thanks, alright.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, in this catcher query service, we have to initialize the, oftash RADIUS connection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just to check, with respect to the credentials are provided or not. Then it comes to our main, keys with respect to my embedding rag, SQL generation result, and the SQL one.
Krish NAik: Then, if, radius URL with respect to radius token, if both the services, like, if both the credentials from config that I'm picking up there into true, then I'll be making the connection to our radius.
Krish NAik: upstash, which is hosted in Upstash to that.
Krish NAik: Now, another thing with respect to semantic catcher a little bit, let's try to discuss. Later on, I'll be jumping into semantic catcher, but what happens in semantic catch? In simple terms, when you think? Because right now, my catcher is not semantic.
Krish NAik: If I say the word semantic, so what is the first thing that comes to your mind?
Krish NAik: Similarity.
Krish NAik: Cosine similarity, biology, okay? Correct. Similarity will come. Now, if you have the embeddings.
Krish NAik: Alright? If you have the embeddings, I'm saving them in my catch-it.
Krish NAik: Later on, some user debt came.
Krish NAik: Okay, based on that query, if something comes into the cache, directly I can pick this result up.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you generate the embedding, and then you try to compare it.
Krish NAik: Think in that perspective.
Krish NAik: Because if you already have an embedding, and then you can generate an embedding, can you do a cosine similarity, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Because you will be having a list of many embeddings. Now, from there, again, the same thing. Now, from there, you might need to pick up the top 3.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's how same catcher works, semantic catcher or same catcher that we call it. Okay, so that's why I'm telling you, if you have this information about the embedded, implementing semantic catcher is not hard.
Krish NAik: Okay, because at the end of the day, you need embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: will… generally, we pick up the top one, okay, but again, there are also some type of validation that we need to add it. Because if… just think about semantic catcher fails, if it returns the wrong result, then what will happen?
Krish NAik: It means that only based on that simulative score, it's not a good practice to take a decision.
Krish NAik: Because if the similarity score matches, then directly you'll be picking up that query, and from the catcher will be throwing it. But at least we need more level of validation. So that's why I told you, that idea of semantic catching, because if you have the embeddings, it becomes much more easier.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, if I have the radius URL and the RADIUS token.
Krish NAik: Semantic search on top of analytics is, in semantic search, a few more things, but more than 60-70% are that same logic.
Krish NAik: Okay, thank you.
Krish NAik: Probably 20%, few other things with respect to multiple validations that I need to check on that.
Krish NAik: Alright, if the conditions are true, the connection is done to abstract radish, okay, and we can save our data, we can read from there, all those things that will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: So, that's why if radish is not installed, simply those input error, finally, my exceptions, and the logger info that I'll be telling.
Krish NAik: Now… One dedicated function to generate my hash using the hashlib package.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, this function, compute hash, then comes serializing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are very common tasks with respect to catching implementation, then comes deserialization, but that's why, one by one, I'll be just calling these functions. So, whenever you are looking into, one is the JSON serialization and the JSON deserialization.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because if I have a Python object, what is the main purpose? And my… what will be my Python object? It will be a dictionary only, no? I can convert a Python dict into a JSON, yes or no.
Krish NAik: That's the main purpose of serialization and deserialization. I hope everybody gets that.
Krish NAik: Now, Mohammad is asking, Redis will be filled up. If we have large differences, only if we have enough memory. Generally, see, if you have more memory.
Krish NAik: the size will be much more higher. In my case, as I showed you in AppStash, it was taking around 20KB. But if you change the embedding dimension, because right now I have 1536, you can take that, okay, if it becomes 3072, then probably from that 20KB,
Krish NAik: directly, you can take it that it will come around close to, like, at least 40, 35 kil.
Krish NAik: So, the size of the radius will increase, if you are going with higher dimensions.
Krish NAik: Higher dimensions, always remember that higher dimensions always comes with a cost. It means that for, even for your vector deal.
Krish NAik: If you are using any cloud-hosted vector DBs, they are also… you are charged based on dimension.
Krish NAik: What will be your vector dimension? Beach contact, those guys will be charging.
Krish NAik: Even for, like, any Milvers, Quadrant, everywhere, the same logic works.
Krish NAik: Now, the same thing. So, for example, if I say about your, vector, like, ha…
Krish NAik: dense vector dimension. These are 1536 and this one. But what about your sparse vector dimensions?
Krish NAik: They are very, very high.
Krish NAik: It generally starts from, like, 12,000 is a good number, until 30,000 that you can provide.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, that's for sparse vectors, again, with the charge.com. So always remember that if you're going with a high… that's why we don't always start our solutions building with a very high vector dimension. The emitting dimension, we always try with something. We start, like, 768, and then finally we move ahead with
Krish NAik: 15.30.
Krish NAik: Yes, people are using… sparse is a common one. Keyword matching is important.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, this is my GET function, retrieve my value from the catcher. Okay.
Krish NAik: If it is enabled, simply, now, this particular implementation, a lot of, code that is from the actual AppStash Redis implementation that I have taken it.
Krish NAik: Josephine, then, why 2 is, 2 sparse?
Krish NAik: See, to build hybrid rack, you need both the things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Everything comes with a charge, for sure, but again, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: These are common practices with respect to traditional RAT practices that we have seen till 2024.
Krish NAik: Everything comes with a charge. That's why. So we only be ignoring, just because of charge.
Krish NAik: That's okay. Because everything, if you really look into LLM paid.
Krish NAik: embeddings, if you are hosting it in your server, then also it becomes paid, even if you go with an open-source model. Okay, so everything is paid, actually, if you look into RAG-based solutions.
Krish NAik: That's why… that's why we tell that. RAG is not completely an open source thing. People might have built an open source placeholder where you need to put your own values, but whenever you will be putting your own credentials, it will be coming with a cost.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this particular function is the main retrieval function from the catcher dev kit that I have.
Krish NAik: And this is the main one. If not, self.enabled, record a miss. So initially, if you are not enabling our caching system, this will be by default return if it is enabled in this particular condition.
Krish NAik: will be looking into arming, so self.client.get key, based on the key that will be passing it, it will try to access the result. Now, if, through that access, if I get my result is equal to none, directly I will say that the catch is missed.
Krish NAik: If the condition is true, then I will say the catch is it. And finally, the deserialization that I'll be performing to convert that JSON into a Python object.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, the exception part that comes, the catcher get error, if some wrong key is passed generally in our system. So, majorly, I have my 4 keys based on that 4 keys. If something comes out of the system, simply this error that you'll be looking into.
Krish NAik: Then why do sparse instead of dens to avoid?
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Then comes, the set. So, get is for retrieval, set is basically storing the value in your catcher with TTL. Now, this is important whenever you are doing, you need to save the information of any type of your query and responses. Okay, so now this particular function, depth set, is responsible to do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the same thing here with respect to my Python object, first serialization them with respect to JSON, and then I am saving that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is the TTL, set with every query. I'll be passing the main TTL and the serialized information that I'll be saving it in the Redis.
Krish NAik: Then comes deleting in my service, if you remember, I have a dedicated, like, catch a query, so you can actually delete keys, or you can delete all the keys for a particular key.
Krish NAik: I have shown this particular route, where you can delete all the, keys, for… because we had 4 keys, so you can actually write the name of the key, and you can delete all of them. If you leave it blank, the idea is to delete every key. So for that particular implementation, I had that tab delete.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, if catcher is enabled, then only this will take place. Okay, so that's why the first initial try condition will come. Client.keys, the pattern, so first of all, we will look that, yes, keys are available or not. If the key is available, then only we can delete it.
Krish NAik: Now, here, for a same key, there can be, multiple keys, because we have a unique hash. Based on that unique hash, you can look into that, because maintaining specific hash lists is better, because my keys.
Krish NAik: Same. But my hash makes it unique.
Krish NAik: All right. Then, one condition is there, generally, for catching validation, and one up stash ready does not support scan, so use keys acceptable. How many of you know Redis scan?
Krish NAik: If you don't know, you can look into this particular concept.
Krish NAik: Upstage doesn't support it, but other Redis services, if you directly take Redis from Redis, actually. So, it's there. Now, what is the benefit of using Upstage Redis? Can anybody tell me? I have told it in the last class, why I've used upstage Redis.
Krish NAik: Okay, only two people could. What about others?
Krish NAik: Okay, if you remember, everything that I built is serverless. That's the main purpose. If I use something, a dedicated cluster, again, I will be getting charged daily close to, like, $2 to $3.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I plan to go for something, a serverless implementation.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes a flash operation in Redis.
Krish NAik: Entire catcher. Now, this is, by default, if nothing is passed from the, route, then actually this take place. Cache first, all keys are deleted.
Krish NAik: So, like, you can delete by key-wise, or delete all the keys. So, this is the first one.
Krish NAik: Then comes your cache key generators. Now, what are the main keys, within our actual… so, within my key, I have nested keys. Okay, for example, if I tell, okay, my means…
Krish NAik: quitting?
Krish NAik: for our RAG, or for our SQL, inside it, what are the other informations that I have taken? So, pretty much a nested, key values tool. So, get embedding key, okay, the catcher key for our main embedding, the 1536 that you have.
Krish NAik: Catch a key for your rack response. This also you needed, the actual rack response. Then comes your SQL generation key.
Krish NAik: Then comes your SQL result key.
Krish NAik: So, for our SQL result, again, at every point of time, you can see that what I'm doing, I'm computing the hash.
Krish NAik: Okay, because key is same, but the hash will be different, guys. So at every point of time, whenever I'm saving it.
Krish NAik: Hash is very, very important whenever you are working with Redis. Hash is a must one.
Krish NAik: I will complete the service, then I will take a breakup. Don't worry.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, based on those 4 keys, I have done it.
Krish NAik: Then comes, yes, now this is statistics tracking, a very, like, record hit for catcher statistics. I have kept it. Again, now this is not important. If you feel that… if you want to use it.
Krish NAik: Okay, how many times you hit the catcher? Okay, and how many times you missed the catcher? Why it is necessary?
Krish NAik: I feel that
Krish NAik: Actually, when you have implemented your catcher in the real world, how many times do you think that catcher will be used?
Krish NAik: Any solution that you guys have worked.
Krish NAik: in your domain, just tell me a rough number. Like, what is the percentage that your catcher gets hit?
Krish NAik: Yes, okay. Kieran, Anirud is telling,
Krish NAik: 20 to 30%, 20 to 30% is higher, Neirut.
Krish NAik: You can say 20-30% once the system is up for the product is launched, and after 1 year or 2 years, that will come. Initially, when you are launching, it's very low. It comes, like, close to 3-10% total.
Krish NAik: You have to understand that. Later on, with respect to time, that increases.
Krish NAik: So, generally, like, if I say that I want to use a cash check, then you have to do the justification also, not to the business team. He will say that why you need it now, initially from day one.
Krish NAik: That 2-3%. Now, there you can say that I can save money in this. Now, you will say, I can save money. He will say that, okay. Then, for Redis also, you need to pay money.
Krish NAik: Really, like, but in long run, actually, it becomes cheaper. So you have to think not from just a short time, but from long time prospect, it becomes much more cheaper.
Krish NAik: Okay? Yes, more so, like, 30% max. That's a rough one. Initially, it becomes, like, only 3 to 10%, but slowly, slowly, like, next year, when you look into a longer perspective, at least 3 to 5 years, then you can set it.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: So these are a few of the stats with respect to your, miss and hit.
Krish NAik: A simple function with respect to get stats, which will help you to show. And then, finally, my health check for my Redis that I have, because this health check I do initially in the first step only, just to check that all the… my Redis is up or not, based on the key and the token that I have passed it in my credentials.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, this service is done. What's the time? This is 1028. Okay, let's quickly discuss the router service. Then, majorly after the break, we will start with the
Krish NAik: Main, deployment part.
Krish NAik: So, now this is the query router service. It's the job, like, of the query, where to go, to which service.
Krish NAik: the three main types that I have kept it. One is SQL. It means that if the query comes, only it will go to the SQL path. Documents means only towards my rack. Hybrid means execute both. Execute SQL also, execute documents also.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this fallback, I have kept it, because if somebody asks such a question, which might fall into this case and this case also?
Krish NAik: Okay, if you… that's why I've kept this particular condition. Otherwise, it's much safer to work with only two.
Krish NAik: But, it totally depends upon the query. That's why I've taken 3 times, because I know the fallback to this hybrid will be in very less percent. Majorly, these two are the main pathways of your query.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, a simple rule-based router, guys. So, this is pretty much a rule-based router that I have. So, for SQL, I have kept these type of keywords, you have to look into the query.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, how many counts? So, I've kept… these are all keywords. So, you can add more and more keywords.
Krish NAik: Okay, and otherwise, you can use an LLM also.
Krish NAik: LLM-based routing.
Krish NAik: Yes, LLM routing? It's available in Llama Index.
Krish NAik: directly.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, see, I have taken a key-based approach.
Krish NAik: Now, if you feel you can do this using an LLM also, that LLM breast routing.
Krish NAik: I think it's not available directly in Langshan, but in Llama Index it is available. I hope you are getting it what I am trying to say.
Krish NAik: You can use this particular logic. Now, this is completely rule-based. Otherwise, you can use an LLM also to do the routing.
Krish NAik: Alright, simply, now for my documents. Now, see, things can be confusing, like, generally, when I use this describe.
Krish NAik: really, I feel that this is somewhere it can be, okay, confusing with these, keywords from SQL also. What is, and based on that, I've kept multiple things. And then comes your hybrid keywords, because this is my third fallback rule where I've kept it, explain, describe.
Krish NAik: Generally, when I was testing this system, I know this was the con. This is actually a bottleneck.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if I ask you, you have to do the optimization with respect to project 2, this is the actual bottleneck that you guys can work with.
Krish NAik: All right,
Krish NAik: Then comes our main routing function that I have, which will help you to do the routing. So, first of all, whatever the query comes.
Krish NAik: Make it into a lower. Check for hybrid keywords first, more specific.
Krish NAik: And the idea is, if you're working with a hybrid, the execution should be parallel.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, check for hybrid keywords, check for SQL keywords, and check for document keywords. Now, if you have those, okay, if it has hybrid keywords, then I'll be looking into, okay, return the hybrid route, return the SQL route, return the documents route.
Krish NAik: Now, get routing confidence. So, I've kept a function,
Krish NAik: Because this is much more rule-based system that I have kept it. So, a simple confidence score for each routing option. So, in that way, it becomes much more easier, but I will say that this is not very much reliable for your learning purpose input, but never use it in production.
Krish NAik: Okay, the… because right here, I feel that in some of the cases, if it feels… okay, it's much more aligned towards your document card.
Krish NAik: So I can say there is some amount of biasness here to this particular confidence score, which will be provided. Okay, so not a very robust one, because it's a completely rule-based system that I have used.
Krish NAik: Alright, so sometimes people use machine learning models also for these type of query, with a text classification approach.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first of all, routing confidence. So, first of all, we need the question, then we'll be looking for the matches with respect to SQL match, document match, hybrid match. Okay, and then calculate the confidence score. Now, this is the actual logic that I've used. Total matches is equal to max of the SQL1 document.
Krish NAik: And finally, through that. Now, really, this approach is not a robust one, just for learning purposes, good.
Krish NAik: Once you have this total matches value, then you can actually calculate the SQL confidence score, the top confidence score, and the hybrid confidence score.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are all confidence scores for the routing mechanism that I have taken. And once you have that, which one will have the higher value from here, you can actually do the execution to that particular route.
Krish NAik: As simple as that. So it becomes much easier in that.
Krish NAik: Now, this particular logic, you can't think about anything much more also, because I don't feel this is very robust, because my range is 0 to 1. Okay, so now this logic, you can develop it from your own algorithmic side.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the written type of a route, so exactly which route is being used, and we will say that, okay, based on the question, the routing decision that I have, and the routing decision that has been taken based on some keyword match.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, that is the entire JSON return time, whenever I'm doing, any type of query execution.
Krish NAik: Now, I've kept it on explained routing, provide a human-readable explanation why.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, again, this is also a rule-based system, based on my previous implementation that I had. Okay, because for routing explanation, if you want it, one is through sports, you can explain them, okay, but otherwise, now this is much more from the SQL side, the user's natural language portion.
Krish NAik: Now, if route is equal to SQL, if route is equal to documents, else it will come to the hybrid in both retrieval and contextual information that you can
Krish NAik: Now, this function is actually calling this getConfidenceRouting, if you look it.
Krish NAik: So, based on that score. But, with respect to the SQL agent, if you remember, you had a key of explanation that is returned by the LLM. Okay, that particular logic also in the return type, you can keep it.
Krish NAik: Just to understand that, yes, this is a SQL query or not.
Krish NAik: So, LLM routing is there directly, so that module I have not discussed, but you can use.
Krish NAik: LLM routing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Can you see here?
Krish NAik: Okay, that's why tell Lama Index is much more powerful as compared to others. Okay, so here, that the user query can take, and a set of choices, defined by metadata. Right now, it's telling, but returns once or more selected choices. You have this inbuilt function.
Krish NAik: of routers. So, here you can see LLM selectors are there, or identityque selectors are also available.
Krish NAik: So that's why I'm telling you, take my implementation, because this is my custom. Otherwise, you can go ahead with Lama Index. In this project, I have not touched Lama or, Llama or the Langchen family. I've kept it pretty much lightweight.
Krish NAik: Okay? But you can use something from this one. So that's why I'm telling the alternative to my implementation, so that you guys can look into this.
Krish NAik: Okay, the explained routing, this logic is also done.
Krish NAik: All right, then finally, I think after the break, we will start with the deployment part. According to the document, step-by-step, even I will start from scratch.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so immediately I have done the core services discussion.
Krish NAik: Okay, now I think we are ready to move ahead with the deployment part.
Krish NAik: Okay, Armani, you can write it in the chat.
Krish NAik: Guys, a 10 minutes timer, or a 15 minutes timer, quickly let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because, really, I've taken a lot of things.
Krish NAik: When I get mixed answer, it becomes very hard for me. But I can say majority of you are with 15, okay? So I would go with 50.
Krish NAik: Arun told 10 minutes, Sanket told 10, others are much more from 15 minutes, so let's take a break, because even I have discussed, go through the code at least once, it's very, very important.
Krish NAik: So, let me take my clock, where is yellow sticky.
Krish NAik: Let me do this.
Krish NAik: Even I'll be doing my breakfast, and I'll be back in 10, if you have anything.
Krish NAik: Then, you can write it in the chat, okay? So, I'll be back in 10.
Krish NAik: And then I'll be looking into that.
Krish NAik: Yes, if somebody has missed the last 3 classes of this project for them, it will be much harder.
Krish NAik: Because in this, like, if you say the learning gap, Project 1,
Krish NAik: was here, and Project 2 is here. Then Project 3, again, I will make it much more down, little bit easier. Because more than 15 students had told me, this project is very, very hard. Okay, so I know. So Project 3, I'll be keeping it much more simpler.
Krish NAik: Alright, people who have missed the last week, at least, I know it will be harder for them, for sure, but try to cooper, because this project gives you a much more learning. So, like, this is the most peak that I have taken.
Krish NAik: then again, I will come little bit, because I will learn much more, like.
Krish NAik: Not a top-to-bottom approach, my learning is much for bottom-to-top.
Krish NAik: Little bit. First of all, start with project, then learn concepts.
Krish NAik: I don't first learn concepts, and then I do my projects, so… it depends upon people to people, that's all.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I've started the timer, let me get my breakfast, or can I be back in time.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I hope everyone is back.
Krish NAik: Mohit Bisari is asking, tomorrow or next project. I don't think tomorrow this, because the deployment and other things are there. Okay, because for you also to do the configurations, it will take time.
Krish NAik: So, next project next week, Saturday, I will be starting.
Krish NAik: Alright, mmm…
Krish NAik: Ivania asking, when would be the next topic in the initial starting of the class? Only I told you, after this, that will be the project 3, because you guys have already learned the core components of hybrid Rack, that's…
Krish NAik: Alright, so first of all… Now we'll be starting the deployment phase.
Krish NAik: Everybody, let me know in the chat. Ready, ready, ready, ready?
Krish NAik: Alright, dexter.
Krish NAik: Before this, let me go to GitHub.
Krish NAik: Okay, so before going to AWS, let's complete the GitHub part, okay? Please, everybody, set your secrets, because you guys… I think…
Krish NAik: Action.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… All these… Secrets. You have to set it, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Take 10 to 15 minutes, and set all of your secrets.
Krish NAik: API gateway URL, leave it blank for now. Only this one, I think you might not be having.
Krish NAik: Other than that, AWS Access Key ID, I think you have it.
Krish NAik: Account ID, you have it. Secret access key, you have it. Database URL, you have it. OpenAI API, you have it. Opic API, you have it.
Krish NAik: Pinecone, all these three, pinecone, you have it. S3 bucket, you need to create a bucket. Whatever the name that you were given for the bucket, that exact bucket name has to be passed here.
Krish NAik: AppStash Redis token, and App StashRedis. So, all this information, you have it, only the API gateway URL, okay, you don't have it. And right now, this is not required also.
Krish NAik: Because initially, I kept it.
Krish NAik: With API Gateway, but that hard limit of 29 seconds, because of that, I switched to function mark. Okay? So, just leave the first one. Other than that, every other secret. Start creating and pasting the value.
Krish NAik: I think in Project 1, we have already done it, so I think by this time, you guys can do it by yourself. Yes or no? Let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, tomorrow, although this project will continue. To do this task, I think you guys will take at least 10 minutes.
Krish NAik: So, do it, just be sure there are no extra blank spaces. Exactly, okay? So, everybody, please do the first step of just one. I think everybody can do it by yourself.
Krish NAik: Only leave the first one, API Gateway URL, don't use it. Other than that, every other key, you have it with yourself.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody, please start doing it, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: I'm choosing API Gateway URL kaya hai, sir. So, like, initially, I planned, using the HT, like, API Gateway. Okay, AWS, so that service.
Krish NAik: like, lambda through that particular routing or PPI gateway, but I removed that part. Right now, we'll be using function URLs.
Krish NAik: It is valid continuously, I think, there are, like, one year.
Krish NAik: I think it's, because generally, my credits are exhausted in one year, but I know if you do a recharge of $6, because for your course also, if I show you how much I put it, I put around…
Krish NAik: $10, I think, for this particular course.
Krish NAik: Until now, it should be best sold to install it.
Krish NAik: I don't have permission to this page, then who has permission.
Krish NAik: Now, what has happened?
Krish NAik: Don't know what happens to Penai platform.
Krish NAik: OpenAI is actually launching to bring ads. How many of you know about that?
Krish NAik: They are right now in pretty much in loss-making.
Krish NAik: No, no, this is the account.
Krish NAik: I think… Okay, yes, it might not be the account that is also correct.
Krish NAik: But I think in your post till now, $10 I put from day one.
Krish NAik: Just wait, I think this one can be their platform.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: Because that is the account that I use generally, but here… let me check. Everybody, please create… start creating your secrets, okay? Don't look into my screen.
Krish NAik: Add all the GitHub secrets.
Krish NAik: Boom.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have close to 7.68.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I know by end of this score, this 7.68 will be, like, 5.
Krish NAik: Okay, it won't be getting clustered so much.
Krish NAik: One example of LG is, can you show it once?
Krish NAik: Alright, yes. Like, you can just click on this green color button in Project 1 I already showed you. Okay, then you can pass whatever the name, like, the main keys that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want the name of those keys, you can get it from here. See, guys? That's why I've shared already the document. If you want to do that copy-paste, go to your docs, new deploy. Okay, so here I think I have kept it. Yes, all of your major secrets that you have.
Krish NAik: Line number 1046, you can look into. Okay, access key…
Krish NAik: The major ones that you have.
Krish NAik: Lambda function URL, I don't think you need it, but, let's see.
Krish NAik: This I generate it, I think, using a command.
Krish NAik: So, directly you can get the secret names from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the optional secrets also needed. So, the total number of secrets…
Krish NAik: Lambda function URL later on, I'll be generating, but from this document, you can get, okay? So you have to just copy the name of Access Key ID, for example.
Krish NAik: paste it here, your main access key, and the value that you'll be having for your own account. I think everybody knows you have to create an IAM user for this particular task, yes or no in the chat.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Alright. If anybody doesn't know, Jenica is asking which user?
Krish NAik: which user… so, for this, you need the AWS account, no? You will be creating a dedicated user. So, for example, if I showed you.
Krish NAik: Where is my AWS account? Okay, here.
Krish NAik: AWS console, if I'd like to log into my console.
Krish NAik: Okay, send me anything in your root account…
Krish NAik: Just wait, let me get the authenticator code.
Krish NAik: So, from here, in Project 1, also, you used an IAM. Okay, so in IAM, you will go to the user section. Okay, so for example, this particular user, you will go to the security credentials, and from here, create a access key.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when we'll be creating the access key?
Krish NAik: For the user that you have created, okay? So, you will be getting something like this.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is your access key. You can download the CSV file for later reference.
Krish NAik: If you, like, you can use the same user, like, in Project 1 that you have done, because I think everybody has downloaded the access case, so the… if you have deleted it, it's a different case, then create a new one. Otherwise, use the same one, I will recommend it.
Krish NAik: I hope, Chanika, you got the reference, which user?
Krish NAik: Okay, total 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12.
Krish NAik: Total 12 secrets, guys, okay? So, just count.
Krish NAik: Once doing the final confirmation, okay? Just leave that API gateway URL. We don't need that. Other than that.
Krish NAik: You have 12 secrets that will be passing it in your GitHub.
Krish NAik: Can you, keep that screen, okay, all right?
Krish NAik: the, the touchscreen you were asking, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, let me just skip this part, yes.
Krish NAik: And one important thing, again, I will say, for the database URL, please use the session puller.
Krish NAik: Okay, don't use the IPv6. In local, it will work, but in Lambda, when I'll be doing the deployment, their IPv6, it won't support. So, for your DWS URL, so just…
Krish NAik: one thing that I'm keeping it in your mind, okay, because in my initial testing, I know many of you have worked with IPv4 with session pull-up. Okay, otherwise, like, if you are working with IPv6, please switch to other session pull-up part.
Krish NAik: Can we have a script to move the .env script to GitHub Actions? Can we have a script to move…
Krish NAik: If you keep the dot only, it is exposed round.
Krish NAik: Generally, you can do it. You have that GH.
Krish NAik: Okay, through GH, you can do it. Like, in your local systems, you can do that.
Krish NAik: But again, for that, that, GitHub package installation and other things that I have to show.
Krish NAik: Okay. Otherwise, through GH, package.
Krish NAik: You can do that, which you are asking.
Krish NAik: Excuse me, guys.
Krish NAik: how do you from IB6 know if you have done that.
Krish NAik: like, if you remember, for the database URL,
Krish NAik: Initially, like, if you check your code.
Krish NAik: Good, yes, gluteus.
Krish NAik: If I show you my.env, So, here in the database. Initially, I used the IPv61. Later on, I switched
Krish NAik: that… To be food. In…
Krish NAik: Superbase, you have that particular option.
Krish NAik: And I discussed this in class, so a few people who were not working in that case
Krish NAik: That is important. So, let me just open it.
Krish NAik: All the projects are paused, actually.
Krish NAik: Then everybody prove to have a check, for your project.
Krish NAik: No, you just keep, through YML deployment to AWS,
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, just keep it in your secrets. Rest, automatically, everything will be picked up.
Krish NAik: Still now, setting the projector turn.
Krish NAik: Leave that part, Mitesh. Lambda function URL, you don't need to put it.
Krish NAik: If you have .gitignore, how it will pick up that .vnv folder, so…
Krish NAik: Because generally it skips if you keep it and not get ignored.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I don't have that particular permission for this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think I changed my GitHub account also yesterday. Even in my system, it won't work, I forgot to do that.
Krish NAik: Just wait to check that.
Krish NAik: Because yesterday, I was pushing something from another OCF verification.
Krish NAik: Let me just return…
Krish NAik: I don't know which one is the savings?
Krish NAik: Okay, because for this PR, actually, you see a verification was required because of that.
Krish NAik: I've changed my GitHub account in my GitHub CLI. Just wait, I will do that.
Krish NAik: And then I will show.
Krish NAik: Empathy.
Krish NAik: Just right before logout, let me check the status, which account.
Krish NAik: Login to Krishnak AI, okay, I need to log out of this one.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Alright, secrets are there, now I got the access to this account.
Krish NAik: I think I need to check the upstream part also.
Krish NAik: Normally, this is fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so Sampat is telling, AWS account routing is from where we have to get the 12-digit number.
Krish NAik: You have to get it from here.
Krish NAik: You can copy this number, account ID.
Krish NAik: Sampat, okay?
Krish NAik: Then, adding secretly is, done. Can I push to GitHub?
Krish NAik: You don't have to push anything, your code will be my fork only, no?
Krish NAik: So, you don't need to, right now, push. There are some other things also that you have to do, Samgat.
Krish NAik: Do it together.give what all, policies will come. Before that, just create the user.
Krish NAik: So, let me just show you what that I have done it.
Krish NAik: You think this is last 5 days ago that I have built it?
Krish NAik: So you can use all this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so admin access, ECR access, S3 access, Lambda full access.
Krish NAik: So, these are the major policies that I have added.
Krish NAik: One is a custom policy, the RAG deployment policy. Leave that part.
Krish NAik: Okay, other than that, these three directly comes, you can select it. If you are creating a user, or later on to that user also, you can add those things.
Krish NAik: Can you please bring the GitHub again? Alright.
Krish NAik: Guitar, guitar.
Krish NAik: I think, yes.
Krish NAik: The speech.
Krish NAik: Take your time and just be sure, guys, there is no mistake. If there is a mistake here, then again, it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Rates, Tiwari is telling, please ping GitHub URL of access key.
Krish NAik: GitHub URL of access key, what is that, Satish?
Krish NAik: GitHub URL of access key?
Krish NAik: the policy.json is there already in your report around.
Krish NAik: Currently, what's showing on your skin. This I can't share, this is specific to my repo. You can't open my secrets.
Krish NAik: Balaji… okay, for upstairs secret, should it go with double quotes? Don't use double quotes. Don't use double quotes.
Krish NAik: Double codes not required.
Krish NAik: Okay, don't use double quotes.
Krish NAik: Never use the V-codes. That's why I don't use it. In ENV, I might have kept it, but no dual track.
Krish NAik: Just reminded me back.
Krish NAik: Later on.
Krish NAik: I'll be sharing one script also, it's easy, but if you have the GitHub package in your local, then you can do a lot more things, rather than do it manually, but for that, you need that GitHub package for automatic ENV parsing.
Krish NAik: or through command line also, you can do. There is a command through that also, you can set it, but…
Krish NAik: do the set manually, then later on I'll be telling it.
Krish NAik: And whatever bucket that you have created, Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Just be sure you are passing the exact name.
Krish NAik: For that particular bucket.
Krish NAik: Rahul is telling text-to-SQL users should have virtual policy access, okay? Again, I'm showing you.
Krish NAik: I will do it step-by-step, not in one shot, but these are the main policies that I have.
Krish NAik: Because some rules I'll be creating when I'll be executing it, command by command.
Krish NAik: I think only for S3 lifecycle, this one that already I provided in your report.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can look into that markdown file, it's available there also.
Krish NAik: Satish is asking where to create these variables in OUT.
Krish NAik: Under GitHub Actions, Satish, in last, Project 1, also, I've discussed the same thing.
Krish NAik: So, how you are not aware of this?
Krish NAik: You have to just go to your, GitHub, just wait, let me go to my GitHub. Okay, so under your repo, for example, like, you have taken a fork of this one, okay, you have to go to the settings, you have to go to…
Krish NAik: Here are the secrets and variables, you have to click on Actions.
Krish NAik: From actions, you'll be getting the repository, new. Only this one.
Krish NAik: I have kept it, initially I tested with admin netxels, that was something.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Generally, when I start, I don't go for granular levels. I just give the admin access, and then I switch to others.
Krish NAik: Don't worry, Millen. If any roller will be coming, we'll be doing it.
Krish NAik: Right now, a role not required.
Krish NAik: Just give, the major permissions. Later on, everything through command line, we can do it. That's why that deployment document is so much big.
Krish NAik: Alright, take 5 minutes, but complete this part.
Krish NAik: How many of you are creating, AWS IAM user again?
Krish NAik: Is there anybody, or you guys are using it from the old one only?
Krish NAik: Not creating. Because last week also, for that S3 backend that I kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, because most of you have done the testing for that, no? So I think it should be there.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, in last week, how you might have done the testing for the S3 files going?
Krish NAik: The document files in S3. That's right.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can do that, Rakesh.
Krish NAik: Just, be sure about the, specific service.
Krish NAik: permissions that I have added, so these are the main ones. If you have these, nothing to worry.
Krish NAik: VANA model? No, no, no, no, no, don't keep VANA things there.
Krish NAik: Don't give one a thing here.
Krish NAik: Ubana things are not required.
Krish NAik: In .envy, we'll be keeping it.
Krish NAik: Because in config, you have control.
Krish NAik: No, no, that policy is a different one.
Krish NAik: That policy is different. Don't look into my one.
Krish NAik: Huh?
Krish NAik: You don't need everything from .AMP. Very specifically, the thing that I have mentioned in my
Krish NAik: Deploy.yml, only those things are required.
Krish NAik: Check deploy.yml file inside .github folder slash workflows malith. From there, you will understand.
Krish NAik: Because, VANA ENVs, those are not secrets, actually. Those are pretty much configurations.
Krish NAik: That you can expose it.
Krish NAik: Here, all the secrets are that you can't expose.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that one.
Krish NAik: Because once you have done it, if you have locally the GitHub package installed in your system, you can do a GH secret list. It will throw out all the secrets of the particular report that you are working with.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you don't have the package, get the start. Just be…
Krish NAik: Verify that everything here, the 12, secrets, should be there.
Krish NAik: No, Satesh, you don't have to create a new repo.
Krish NAik: Take a fork of mine.
Krish NAik: Why you need to create a new repo?
Krish NAik: Yes, quotes are not required.
Krish NAik: where the YML file is.
Krish NAik: Okay, the YML files will be there, no?
Krish NAik: So, for example, where is my tria? In tria, you will be having this .gitub folder, there you'll be having deploy.
Krish NAik: Okay, Melind, from here, you can check that quick.
Krish NAik: Alright, Muhammad.
Krish NAik: Next time, that's why, I'll be keeping the batch update early in the morning, in our next batch, probably. Like, morning 6.30 is fine. You guys can let me know a little bit.
Krish NAik: I think morning, 6.30, Because then US guys won't have any problems.
Krish NAik: 6.30 or 7 a.m. is also fine, then majorly, because I know most of the students drops in between. That becomes a problem for me.
Krish NAik: Because in morning only, if you complete the batch, then you have your complete day with you. Anything you can do the entire year. That's why. Morning.
Krish NAik: India, it's too early, I know, but again, so sick for me also.
Krish NAik: My… I wake up late, but at least for Saturday, Sunday, I have to do that survey.
Krish NAik: Because morning, if things are done, then, yeah, I feel in morning, things become… goes to it much more clear, fresh mind. That's why… because in the next batch, I was planning.
Krish NAik: Okay, because that's like…
Krish NAik: For the advanced version of this particular rag with LLM badge that I'm planning, then I will keep it in the morning, 7. Because by 10, you guys will be free.
Krish NAik: No, it's just, one thought that I had.
Krish NAik: Because if students drop in between, it becomes a problem for me only.
Krish NAik: once, you have done the set, so if you have the GitHub package… okay, so generally, having this package is useful, because for me also, I don't set all the secrets one by one, so you have a direct command through that, you can actually, like,
Krish NAik: Put all your peer secrets.
Krish NAik: It will be, like, June, July, not now.
Krish NAik: First, the GenAI batch will come, then the Agents 3.2 batch will come.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then the advanced one, or the RAC 2.0.
Krish NAik: So, once you guys, have confirmed that everything is done, let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Because everything is documented directly from Markdown, you will just do copy, paste, copy, paste, copy, paste.
Krish NAik: Yes. VLM part, it will come, but later on.
Krish NAik: Because in that advanced one only, I will put VLLMs also.
Krish NAik: But I have to see, actually, like, how many from this batch, how many students are interested.
Krish NAik: Because in advanced batch, that is the main pain point that we do face, like, we get very, very less enrollments.
Krish NAik: But, one pilot batch, I can't take a test. Like, RAG, I have taken the initiative similarly for… like, I… there are a few only RAG modules, as you guys already know. I'll be keeping it short, then…
Krish NAik: I'll be focusing on SLMs much more, because actually in industry, people work with SLMs more, rather than LLMs, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Whenever you are doing anything custom.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in those cases, SLMs, and SLM from the Liquid AI family, I really love them. They are really, really good. So, probably, like, Liquid AI part, I will add it.
Krish NAik: So once this is done, probably in the month of March, ending or April, I'll be taking your inputs.
Krish NAik: Because he is…
Krish NAik: 50% input I will be putting, Mike, but at least what is your requirement that I will ask, and one-to-one session, we will do it, and we will discuss.
Krish NAik: And this…
Krish NAik: Deba too secret, huh? You can use that GH, but that's the main thing, you should have the secret part in your own one.
Krish NAik: If you have that package in your system, you can do in that way also.
Krish NAik: No restriction. Or you can create a simple bash script, and you can execute that script.
Krish NAik: Using a for loop, one by one, it will do the parsing inside a .env file, and it will push.
Krish NAik: Okay, only 1 or 2% are told already, okay? Let's wait for others also.
Krish NAik: Because that's why I know tomorrow's class also will be going in the deployment phase.
Krish NAik: Because a lot of things are here.
Krish NAik: Oh… Right now, I'm not interested. Like, I don't have time also to consult.
Krish NAik: Like, I'm pretty much packed for the next months.
Krish NAik: Mitesh, do we need to make sure that the repository want to keep public? Right now, it's public. Later on, you can keep it as private also. No issues in that.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can keep it. There is no restriction in that part.
Krish NAik: Mmm…
Krish NAik: So, I'm creating a .env… okay.env is actually not required, because I won't be picking… it's in .gitignore Methesh.
Krish NAik: No, who is asking? Melinda, I think? Yes.
Krish NAik: It's only for local when I do the testing, then only .env is required. During the deployment, it will be picked up these secrets that I have kept it, so…
Krish NAik: My.invas and dot getignored, so it doesn't get pushed together.
Krish NAik: Take credit goes in action, correct?
Krish NAik: Mmm, okay. Vanna, and Peter, much more.
Krish NAik: From the configuration settings. Those are not actual secrets, so you can expose those things.
Krish NAik: So, just be sure this GitHub Secrets, and when you have created the… or any IAM user, just keep this one. All this…
Krish NAik: Full access, like, S3 full access, Lambda full access, okay, and ECR full access. If you have this, then we are good to proceed with the next steps.
Krish NAik: So, guys, please let me know once you are ready.
Krish NAik: LLModelM tell me that it's not required any secrets.
Krish NAik: not require gene callscape API Gateway.
Krish NAik: That service we are not using.
Krish NAik: DSR Vijit. Last week only, I shared the deployment link.
Krish NAik: Everything. Copy, paste, copy-paste. Okay, so you don't really need to care about the comments.
Krish NAik: Let me check which user I'm using, and I forgot, because in the other patch, I was using a different user.
Krish NAik: This text was equal, or agony.
Krish NAik: How many more minutes said, guys? I think for most of you, it should be done.
Krish NAik: I know it takes 10 to 15 units, but not more than that, I think.
Krish NAik: So, generally, with respect to the checklist, what are the things that you have? So…
Krish NAik: your AWS, I knew there.
Krish NAik: Okay? With, the policies that I have shown, Then comes your S3 bucket.
Krish NAik: Okay, so your S3 bucket should be created.
Krish NAik: Then comes your GitHub secrets. These are the only things that you need.
Krish NAik: Melind is asking, I am done, but not sure which MDF file you are talking about.
Krish NAik: which MD file is there in GitHub only, no? So, go here. You can check the docs folder, D-O-C-S Docs. Inside Docs, you have the new deploy.md.
Krish NAik: JCR also you need it, correct?
Krish NAik: you're… ECR repository.
Krish NAik: You got it.
Krish NAik: these two things are the, these, I think, major ones, because right now, in my code, once we start ACRS3, everything will be creating. If you don't want, don't create it manually.
Krish NAik: As simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, at least for now, I know that at least these two things are important. The other two are, like, later on in the code, I've kept that, that, through command line, I'll be creating everything. So, if these two things are done, you can let me know.
Krish NAik: I think, what's the time? I will wait for 5 more minutes, then I will start. Okay, so 5 more minutes, 11.48, I will start.
Krish NAik: But I've given enough time.
Krish NAik: Yes, Sampat, do we need to… yes, don't worry if I show you here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you will see, like, everything.
Krish NAik: Lambda executions, then I think I'll be having that
Krish NAik: I'll be attaching policies. Everything is through command line. Bucket also, I'll be creating the bucket from here.
Krish NAik: I have added it. ECR rep also I'll be creating from here. Okay, so everything from here, don't worry.
Krish NAik: That's why this deployment is a little bit, longer.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I know, at least 50% we'll be doing today. Let's see, like, how much we can do it. Rest of the things we will do it tomorrow.
Krish NAik: Can you put that policy page back? Policy page, which is that… it's there in new underscore deploy.md, and only one policy is required, I think, that I have provided, which is the S3 catchy policy.json.
Krish NAik: That's the major one. I think trust policy is not required, but let's go through that, because 3 times I've done the testing through this document with respect, that's why I've updated it also, but most of the things looks good.
Krish NAik: Can you policy page back, okay, AWS policies you are talking about, yes, AWS policies, quickly check.
Krish NAik: By default, keep the admin one, okay, because otherwise, if something is getting missed, that's why, for safety, later on, you can remove that.
Krish NAik: Then comes your ECR full access, S3 full access, Lambda full access.
Krish NAik: Anshul, yes, yes, Langraph will be going. No, only one framework is there in this course, so for sure, Aangshu will go that in detail.
Krish NAik: If there were 5 things noted.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, quickly, complete, guys, within 5 minutes from 11.50, let's start.
Krish NAik: RAC deployment policies kept available, not required.
Krish NAik: Okay, Balaji, if you are done, good. Just wait for others to complete.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'll be back in 2 minutes. So, others, please complete. From 11.50, we'll start.
Krish NAik: others who have done it, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Two persons have stolen at da-da.
Krish NAik: Others also, please confirm in the chat, turn, run.
Krish NAik: A thumbs up, something like that, do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, 10 to 15 responses I got.
Krish NAik: Anybody in North Dunn State till now?
Krish NAik: Because I think it should be done. I've given you enough time.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay, a few more people.
Krish NAik: One more minute, and then we will start.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, just have a check, okay, like, just type this command and be sure you are in the correct, because I think you guys already done AWS configure.
Krish NAik: Okay. That step, who has not done it, I think most of you have done it in the last class also.
Krish NAik: So… do that step.
Krish NAik: Lenovo, not required for that. Wrike deployment policies kept it.
Krish NAik: No, you don't need to copy anything, Aru.
Krish NAik: From your previous project, nothing is related, so nothing copying or anything like that. Everything is pretty much isolated and standalone.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think it's already 11.50, I think I can start.
Krish NAik: Let me touch on the cam…
Krish NAik: All right. So, I think AWS configure part, you guys have done it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you can directly open the Markdown document parallelly. Okay, please open it. Because here, all the other steps are there. Install AWS CLI and other things, but I think most of the things are installed in your system as per Project 1 discussion. So, directly, you can start from AWS Configure.
Krish NAik: Okay, so AWS configuration also, I think most of you have done, you will be getting a prompt like this. Yes or no?
Krish NAik: default output format, it's not necessary to keep it just on, just hit enter. Blank is also fine. Yes, let me know. AWS configure parts, locally, it is authenticated with the AWS cloud.
Krish NAik: If somebody has created a new user for them, it is required, the AWS configure part.
Krish NAik: Because, once you do AWS configure, it will be, you will get the prompt with AWS access key, ID, secret key, region, okay? So, these things that will come. So, you have to set these things for local authentication.
Krish NAik: I think for most of you, it's done, and once it's done, you can do, like, AWS STS get caller identity.
Krish NAik: just, get the verification that it is the same user, because my username is Text2SQLRAC.
Krish NAik: Please let me know in the chat, guys.
Krish NAik: Yes, for how many of you?
Krish NAik: You can get the verification, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Got the verification, got the verification.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, the next thing is, just be sure you have opened the Markdown file.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody has opened the Markdown file.
Krish NAik: In your text editor, so that you can quickly copy-paste it in your terminal.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Could not get preview new deploy.
Krish NAik: I think you will get it, I have the file, I'm just using the extension of that, I think.
Krish NAik: mark down an answer or something like that, I forgot that name extension.
Krish NAik: Which one is mine one?
Krish NAik: Yes, markdown preview enhanced. If you do the installation of this, you will get a view like this.
Krish NAik: If you don't get a view, open GitHub. Okay, it's not necessary that you have to open it from here also. I think from GitHub also, you can get it. You can open, automatically, markdowns are rendered in.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can follow this part. I will start from, step… I can see which step is this one. Like, 2.3.
Krish NAik: AWS CLI configuration, sir.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here, this is the main part AWS configure, STS caller identity. Okay.
Krish NAik: And I've kept some export and eco-commerce just for your own verification. And, remember, when I'm working with variables, it's fine. So you can set the variables, or, you can directly,
Krish NAik: Hard-coded.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in whichever way you like it, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think we can start with the first, the lambda execution rule, because I have given full access, so you guys can create the rule. So you can just copy-paste this command.
Krish NAik: In your terminal.
Krish NAik: Have I provided the, trustpolicy.json? Okay, so, in your case, I think the name will be trustpolicy.json. It's the same file if I show you in my one, where is the text editor.
Krish NAik: Just wait.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have that trust policy.json.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you, check the code here, this is exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that it's already there. I think in everybody's repos, you have the trust policy.json. Using the cat command, I'm creating the file. I hope everybody understands Linux commands.
Krish NAik: Because few Linux commands that you can see here.
Krish NAik: But in Windows, do CAT works? If…
Krish NAik: Because, in Windows, I don't think CAT works. Yes, guys.
Krish NAik: Because, I am on Mac, in Mac it works. Otherwise, just copy-paste that file. See, this content you can copy-paste this also.
Krish NAik: If you have a Git Bash, it will work, I know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the same piece of code which is kept here.
Krish NAik: Okay, just, don't use the last line and the first line. Rest thing you can… but I think I have shared, please do a confirmation. Trustpolicy.json, you guys have it.
Krish NAik: In your own repo, that's why I shared the file.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: If you have the trustpolicy.json, what is the next step? You have the command for that. You need to create the rule. So this is the rule that I'll be creating. Okay, you can just, copy-paste and just,
Krish NAik: if you have created, so you can pass the file path here, because in my case, it's temp, because actually I was creating these things in the temp folder.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, for example, if I already have that.
Krish NAik: So let me just copy the command here.
Krish NAik: I will go to my command line.
Krish NAik: But if you don't have the command, if you don't… because I know everybody has the file. If you don't have the file, then only this is it. This command will only create the file. And later on, once I have the policy.json file with me, then I will create that I am. Okay, and you will…
Krish NAik: get enough.
Krish NAik: output something like this, because then my identity already exists, so I will just show you that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you can park, like, for example, slash temp, I can pass…
Krish NAik: So… Okay, so I think lambda is needed.
Krish NAik: So, in my case, you can see entity already exists. Okay, in your case, the entity won't be available. Okay, and you will be getting… so I've kept the output also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the first step that you have to do.
Krish NAik: Please confirm, guys, how many of you
Krish NAik: just remove this slash temp from here and lambda also. Just keep trust policy. In your case, the name of the file is trust hyphen policy.
Krish NAik: Role created. Can you see something like this, an expected output? Something like this, you can see it.
Krish NAik: Role created. Everybody, please let me know once the rule is created.
Krish NAik: Because it's simple, copy, paste, copy, paste.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, fine, fine, you don't need to paste the output. That's the only thing, I was looking.
Krish NAik: Because if you try to run the same command, you will get this entity already exists.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can have a check for that.
Krish NAik: Tell me, can I proceed to the next step?
Krish NAik: Because you just need to copy-paste most of the things.
Krish NAik: If anybody is getting an error, let me know in the chat at least.
Krish NAik: Because,
Krish NAik: Jenica, the path will be remove this slash 10 slash lambda. Just keep the original file name, trust policy.json. That's the thing that even I have done it, no. I've just removed. File.2 slashes will be there, don't remove those slashes, and directly the name of the file.
Krish NAik: I hope nobody's getting any error.
Krish NAik: Yes, or guys, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: remove slash temp, Rahul. See, if you're in Mac, if you are working with this, see, why I've kept it? The idea was that you guys will be executing this command, and this gets created in the slash temp folder.
Krish NAik: Okay? But in our case, it's in our root directory, so I don't need this slash type. I hope everybody gets a simple path thing that you need to fix it.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, correct, correct.
Krish NAik: There is no issue in that.
Krish NAik: assume role document 2000, Lambda Actionable AWS. This looks good to me. There is, no issue in that.
Krish NAik: Okay, Rahul, I think you can fix it. Because slash temp… and generally, I think slash temp is available in Linux and Mac only.
Krish NAik: Okay, so remove this part, and just give trust policy.json, and you can create it. Now, once the IAM rule is created, you need to attach it with your lamina.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, like, you can directly copy this.
Krish NAik: Okay, and paste it.
Krish NAik: Similarly, in your command line.
Krish NAik: You won't be getting any output in this case.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because the rule name, what I have given here, previously, RAG Lambda execution rule, and the same rule name I am. So this time, I'm attaching it with AWS Lambda.
Krish NAik: somebody is telling, getting an error, account ID, I'm attached.
Krish NAik: Just wait, account ID is there, let me just see here.
Krish NAik: Because I don't think the hair in this,
Krish NAik: I can't see any type of, account ID variable which is getting used.
Krish NAik: So, whoever has pasted that error, Melind.
Krish NAik: Okay, till now. Because, see, generally, when you have a variable, okay, so for that particular variable, directly past your accounting.
Krish NAik: replace that variable with your account ID. That's why I have to keep it as a variable length. I hope you get that.
Krish NAik: your AWS account ID, that 12-digit number will be different, and mine will be different.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: You can export that variable later usage, but I will, like, hard-coding it for now.
Krish NAik: Everybody, like, whenever you see a variable, just, be sure you are using your own variable, because my variable and your variable won't be the same.
Krish NAik: Alright, is this part done?
Krish NAik: Please let me know, then directly you can paste it.
Krish NAik: Because once this you have done, you can directly paste it again. Now, this is the policy for me, it's already attached. In your case, you will see no output. It means that, yes, attachment is done.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: for everybody.
Krish NAik: The policy that you created, is it attached with Lambda for everybody? I think it should be done. Alright.
Krish NAik: Yes, like, you can do the export of those variables in your own environment, Sampat, there is no issue in that. But right now, if you don't want hard-coded.
Krish NAik: P?
Krish NAik: Because if you create a variable in something, error comes, it becomes much more problematic. Again, you have to export the new version of the variable.
Krish NAik: Alrighty. Now, my policy is attached. Now, for S3, the next thing. So, step by step, I am going, first of all, created an IAM rule. That IAM rule, I have attached it with AWS Lambda.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now, the next step, now for this, what you will be getting, all the CloudWatch logs. Okay, now comes to your S3 permissions. This S3policy.json file also I have provided. In your repo, you can see that.
Krish NAik: Because right now, as I'll be working with that bucket, so multiple types of operations that I'll be doing, so that's why GET object, put object, delete object, list bucket, all these things that I've kept it in the actions.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, in the same way.
Krish NAik: What you can do, because you already have this file, so directly, you can, like, if you want, first of all, create the policy.
Krish NAik: and then attach the policy to Lambda.
Krish NAik: So, the same step that needs to be followed, okay? In my case, if I try to create the policy, it will tell me that it's available.
Krish NAik: So, step by step.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just be sure this path, you are handling it correctly.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the path in my case. If I show you, where is my lambda? You have… do you have the lambda policy?
Krish NAik: I don't think S3catcherPolicy.json, okay? In your case, the name of the file is different, s3catcherPolicy.json, okay? Like,
Krish NAik: this file name, then I will change it to this, so just S3, hyphen, catch it, policy.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you exactly step by step. Go slow, but do all the steps correctly.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you really check the content of this file, and always look into exactly the content that we are using.
Krish NAik: And here you can see very specifically the, resource. Now I've kept it, like, Rag Catcher Bucket is basically the name that I'm planning.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is actually the main bucket name that I… I'm passing it.
Krish NAik: Okay,
Krish NAik: Otherwise, we can create, first, and we can do it later. Because till now, I think you guys have not created that S3 bucket, so that's the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just follow the naming conventions that I am using. If you change something, just be sure we have to do that particular update.
Krish NAik: Through temp, also, we can do create… yes, yes, yes. Generally, these files are not required, so I keep those files in temp. It's not related to the project, but for your understanding, you should at least look into the file. That's the main purpose of sharing these things.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, here, the name of this fine here is 3 hyphen catcher hyphen policy.json.
Krish NAik: I think it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in my case, NKT already exists. In your case, you'll be getting an output, just like last time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so an output like this.
Krish NAik: And once you have this, you have to attach it. So when you do this, here is a variable.
Krish NAik: W is account ID. It means that you will copy this command, you will paste it here, and then this account ID that you have, you need to delete this account ID.
Krish NAik: Okay, and you have to paste your own account ID. From here, you will be getting, I think everybody knows, go over here and copy this, your account ID. Okay, and paste it here.
Krish NAik: You can do this, or you can export it as a variable also. That is also fine, I have no issues, then you can use that dollar sign if you are doing that export option.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: Once I do this, you will see that, okay.
Krish NAik: No error means everything is correct.
Krish NAik: I'm using the same, so follow my variables only. Now, if you start giving different names, you have to handle it, just be sure. TJ.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: The policy name? Yes, the policy RN, this should have a match.
Krish NAik: Because here, the policy name is LAC lambda S3 Access. So that's why the policy name has to match. If you give a different name, and if you are creating different, it won't work. I think, for everybody, these steps are working.
Krish NAik: Yes, from AWS caller identity also, you can get it, so I'm correct. Like, if you have opened. Otherwise, from here also, you can see this is the account ID that you can copy and paste it. That is also fine, I have no issues.
Krish NAik: Because, you know, the steps are really big, so if something happens in between, okay, then again.
Krish NAik: starting from scratch, it will take time, because for me, also, I have to sit for at least 1 or 2 hours to do these things.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is your GitHub Actions policy.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, here I've kept, like, add the deployment permissions to the user, create it in section. I think you will be creating one IAM user for that particular user. Okay, because right now, we'll be doing the deployment using the same user. Otherwise, you can create a different user only for the GitHub Actions deployment.
Krish NAik: So, if you want, you can copy this file. I don't think I have
Krish NAik: Provided this file, okay? So let me just check.
Krish NAik: So you can copy this one.
Krish NAik: Let me check… Trust policy S3… no, I have not provided this file with you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so what you can do…
Krish NAik: So, first of all, if you want to create, just copy this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and I will push this file also, so for you, it becomes much easier.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just baste it here.
Krish NAik: And right now, let me just remove, 10. Let me keep it. GitHub Actions Policy JSON.
Krish NAik: And I will hit enter. Okay, so this file got created. You can see now, this policy, GitHub action policies. I will push that file. Just be sure in this file, there is a variable.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that variable, you need to update it.
Krish NAik: somewhere, I think, with respect to the variable part.
Krish NAik: Just wait, because from here, I have copied it.
Krish NAik: resource, okay. This is the main AWS account ID. This variable needs to be updated.
Krish NAik: S3 part, I think, for everybody is, executed.
Krish NAik: This is a different one? S3 Lifecycle.json?
Krish NAik: I think lifecycle.tes one I have not done, only the catch-up policy I have done till now.
Krish NAik: Yes, next one, okay.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So, everybody, just be sure you are using your own AWS account ID here. This part, you can update it here.
Krish NAik: Let me just make it a little bit smaller.
Krish NAik: Because AWS Lambda set alright.
Krish NAik: Yes, corrective RAG, self-reflective RAG, yes, those things, for sure. Those are part of RAG only, no? Why don't teach?
Krish NAik: Once you have this file, the same way, you can just
Krish NAik: Be sure, again, attach the policy.
Krish NAik: Okay, the GitHub Actions policy that you are doing it right now?
Krish NAik: You can just copy this file, Paste it.
Krish NAik: Policy team, just be sure you have removed this part.
Krish NAik: No, no, today, Milinde, it is not possible for me to complete. Neither for others also.
Krish NAik: So many changes are there, so it's not, possible.
Krish NAik: Okay, in my case, it already exists. Once you have created that specific role for your GitHub Actions deployment, the next thing, again, attach it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here, AWS account ID is very, very important. Just be sure you are passing your correct AWS account ID.
Krish NAik: Okay, this part.
Krish NAik: Because right now, that's why I'm manually doing it from CLI, it's much easier for everybody to follow.
Krish NAik: tailor for deployment user, I,
Krish NAik: Don't think I have done it because of that instantly.
Krish NAik: But it's fine, not an issue.
Krish NAik: Okay, so step by step, just follow each step.
Krish NAik: Now, how many of you created the bucket?
Krish NAik: Because right here, based on your account, AWS account ID, you are creating it, but just be sure that if you want to, do that, if you already have a bucket, it's fine. Otherwise, just create the bucket. To create a bucket, this is the command.
Krish NAik: For how many of you, the bucket is here? Because, see, here is 3 bucket name, again.
Krish NAik: Because this S3 bucket name has to be exactly this name that you have passed in your GitHub secrets.
Krish NAik: Okay, so where is your GitHub secrets?
Krish NAik: Okay, I think here, let me just duplicate.
Krish NAik: So, whatever that exact thing should be there. If you already have the bucket, it's fine, I have no issues, you don't need to create a new bucket.
Krish NAik: But, according to this.
Krish NAik: Secrets, you have to maintain that.
Krish NAik: Okay, S3Catcher bucket, this is the exact bucket name. Even in your local config.py, you have that bucket name. So just be sure the bucket name that you are using is consistent everywhere.
Krish NAik: All great.
Krish NAik: Because, yes, you need the deployment user, Just wait. So…
Krish NAik: All right, so Majorly, I think this, part with respect to this…
Krish NAik: Now, if you want, this is optional, like, if you want to enable versioning in your bucket, you can do this.
Krish NAik: Okay, ACL versioning that comes with every S3 bucket, if you want, you can apply it, but this is optional, not recommended. So, any step where option is written, you can do that. Now, this is a,
Krish NAik: simple, policy that I've kept it for my S3 bucket.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, here, like, automatically delete old catch-up documents after 30 days to save cost. Okay, now it's not necessary, you delete it, rather than you can move to a much cheaper service, like S3 Glacier. Okay, so I think this one is selling, so this place also you can do that, so…
Krish NAik: you can just copy and the same way, because S3Lifecycle.json, have I provided that file?
Krish NAik: There's 3 catch-up policies there.
Krish NAik: no lifecycle.cs1 file, I have not, shared with you. But again, this is optional, not necessary for you to compulsory do it, okay? So you can test it out later on.
Krish NAik: Because even I… I think I tested it in the first step, later on I have not done it.
Krish NAik: So… just wait, I need to delete this file from here.
Krish NAik: Let's remove slash temp, S3 rules.
Krish NAik: I'm just testing, you guys can skip, so it's not necessary that every step that you are doing
Krish NAik: Okay, we need to do the execution of that.
Krish NAik: Here, this delete old catch, this, you are telling this ID has to be in… entirely in caps, Murthada.
Krish NAik: All right, because, let me see…
Krish NAik: which ID? Because here… okay, this one. Are you talking about this ID?
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, friend. So probably when then I will update it in the Markdown document, just with…
Krish NAik: Because if you have done the testing, it's fine.
Krish NAik: Because this part, I think I skipped even in my step, just to it.
Krish NAik: This is a preview.
Krish NAik: Where is the Moncton 5 depth stock? Okay, let's just wait till…
Krish NAik: Alright, I've upgraded to the markdown file also, so I will push it.
Krish NAik: Okay, few files, this one and this one. Okay, so… I'll push it in one shot, because I know you guys can create the file already, that part is done, so let me just execute this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, once this is done, then I can directly execute this one.
Krish NAik: So here, when you're doing it, just be sure the bucket name, this is a dollar. Whatever the bucket that you are using, okay, you are exactly using the same bucket.
Krish NAik: In my case, what's the pocket name, even? I forgot just to it.
Krish NAik: All right. Now, again, this is optional if you want. Okay, you can do a verification of the bucket based on that, so RAT catcher.
Krish NAik: Okay, he will be getting an output. Now, the next step comes is, creating your ECR repository. I think till this point, everybody is done with respect to buckets and other things, the permissions.
Krish NAik: please let me know, because at least let's complete the, I think, ECR part and these things that we can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, let's do these simple steps, because directly from here you can do it, it's not tough.
Krish NAik: This is much easier. If you want, you can directly create. See, in my case, like, I create the repository, I'm giving a different name because I think this already exists in my case, so I will just add an hyphen 123. You don't need to add that. Okay? So, you create it.
Krish NAik: So, this will create your ECR repo, and you will see something like this.
Krish NAik: And from here, actually, the main important thing is this repo URL.
Krish NAik: Yes, this is the most important thing, because here, your Docker build-in, the images that you'll be building.
Krish NAik: Whether in GitHub Actions, okay, or from your local, it will be pushed here.
Krish NAik: So, this is important. In my case, I have added 123, it is not required in my… in your case.
Krish NAik: So, just a confirmation again, don't add hyphen 123.
Krish NAik: biology getting error in, put, there, just to be sure you are using capital ID.
Krish NAik: Okay? Otherwise, I will look into that, don't worry.
Krish NAik: Alright, if this is done, it means that your ECR part is done. Okay, you will be getting something like an output. See, you can export it as a variable, it's totally optional, but, otherwise, just be sure you will be copy-pasting this URI most of the times. So that's why, through this, I have to
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: I really, like, if you want to build the image and push the image, you can do it from your local. Okay, so right now, as you can see, this is the Docker build. You can do the testing of this one from your local machine.
Krish NAik: So, till now, I think, let me check if my docker is running or also not. Because now, coming to local.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, just wait. Let me just, I think it's blank, everything.
Krish NAik: Paul internal, so…
Krish NAik: I think some update is going on here. Okay, so I think everybody can do the build, you have the Docker file.
Krish NAik: See, now, I have two Docker files.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's discuss about the file also a little bit.
Krish NAik: So, what is there in the Dockerfile? So, two Dockerfile, one is for lambda, which is required. So, that dockerfile.lambda is very specific, but for your local, this is the main one.
Krish NAik: Docker file. Now, if you are… if you want to do a local testing, you can actually run, this file, or basically, when you are building the image, directly, you can use this one.
Krish NAik: So, from here, so Python 3.12, slim as base.
Krish NAik: Few environment variables just for Python that I have passed. Now, few things that I have installed. Okay, now, all these things are dependency for your, like, PDF processing, because Tesseract you need to install, PopperUtils, LibMagic, GCCG++, these are all requirements for that.
Krish NAik: So, very specifically, I am telling run, which means the execution of these commands.
Krish NAik: This is part clear. So, what are these packages doing? I hope everybody knows that even when we, when we were working with, docklings, or even Unstruct Chip, they had a backend of Tesseract. So, for Tesseract.
Krish NAik: have done this.
Krish NAik: Okay, so these are packages required for your Ubuntu.
Krish NAik: Right now, as for my base image, this is based on Debian, so pretty much like Ubuntu, you can think.
Krish NAik: Okay, then once I have that, finally, this is my working directory. Okay, so this is the main part with respect to your dependency installation, requirement.txt. I'm copying that file in the Docker environment.
Krish NAik: And then I'm doing, like, first of all, I have… I have added no one script, location, and then requirement. You can add it no…
Krish NAik: Catcher directory also. Alright, so, like, no catcher, so that is also fine.
Krish NAik: Once this is done, my main, working directory, few things that I'm copying…
Krish NAik: So, for example, my app folder to there. So, very specifically, I'm not copying all the files. This is much more optimized. Otherwise, what I can do? Copy dot dot. I think everybody can understand. Copy dot dot. Generally, when we want to copy everything from source to destination. But here, very specifically, I've told only these files are required.
Krish NAik: Then comes,
Krish NAik: In this particular image, I'm just creating a folder, data.uploads, where your original files that will be getting uploaded. Later on, this will be moved from, like, from this image to S3.
Krish NAik: And finally, this is my application startup command. Okay, so this is just a health check. Through that health check, I am accessing that, okay, once my application starts, that everything works or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is my main local one. So you can do a build if you feel that, if you want to do a local testing, it's fine. Otherwise, you can skip this.
Krish NAik: Because the build will take time. So, for example, right now, if I do this particular build, okay? So, let me just show you. The build will take time, because, my main build architecture, I moved from ARM64,
Krish NAik: to this one. Okay, now you can see URI, this part, okay. Now, this is a tag that I generally use, it becomes much easier. You can copy this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and later on, I can tag it and push it directly.
Krish NAik: So, very key. And now this build, why, like, hyphen hyphen platform Linux AMT64? Because I am in Mac. So, that's why I'm telling that use this particular platform.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise it's not necessary to pause the platform. In my case, the default one is ERM64. I hope everyone knows that.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, right now, even for our build, I have picked up the dockerfile.lambda.
Krish NAik: Okay, because in our case, I need to talk about Magnum, which I'll be doing tomorrow. I have not
Krish NAik: really done the discussion for that, but you can test out the bit. Now, this one in here, I have done few optimizations with respect to the Docker file here.
Krish NAik: Now, this Dockerfile, when you are actually doing it, can you see here I have very specifically, taking UV?
Krish NAik: Because you know that if I do a simple pip install, it will take a lot of time.
Krish NAik: So I've taken UV for here, and then directly, like, UV, the pencil, I can do the package. Now, whenever you are working with AWS Lambda, you need dedicated Lambda images. Okay, so now this is the Lambda image for Python 3.12 that I have taken, and this is my main builder image. So that's why, as builder, that I have taken into.
Krish NAik: Okay, and later on, like, I will be using UV to do the installation, otherwise it takes a lot of time if you are not using UV. At least, I can say one or two minutes will be reduced.
Krish NAik: Okay, then few, UV variables that need to be set according to the official Docker Hub image. Okay, so that's why all these things that I have configured here.
Krish NAik: Then comes installing those packages according to your lambda, like DNS install, popular utils, GCC, G++, and finally, I'm training, everything, okay? So, that's why, like, from your local
Krish NAik: to AWS Lambda, these things are different. Then I'm copying the requirement.txt.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, a few things that I am mounting within the image. Okay, so, for example, where my UV. Now, these are all related to UV. If you're working with UV, see, again, working with UV is not necessary.
Krish NAik: But I felt that the build time during our deployment, it will get reduced to 2-3 minutes. That's why I'm using this one. As you can see, UVPIP install.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because if you're doing with UV, you need to follow the instructions which are mentioned in the official docker.
Krish NAik: hop, basically. From there, I have actually looked, and I have taken these settings.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Then, it comes, like, copy app, then lambda task root, it means that what will be the root directory in your lambda when it will be executing, and what will be the main entry point of your application? The main entry point will be the lambdaHandler.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is the main entry point that becomes.
Krish NAik: And then setting some permissions with respect to file accessing for Lambda, like CH mod. 755, you can use 777 also, it's not necessary. 644, I've kept it bare minimum for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the final runtime image, okay, is this one. So, as I was testing with multiple, things, but I have removed a lot, okay, so as you can see, a lot of other dependencies.
Krish NAik: for unstructured and docklink both, which were there, okay? But if you want, you can do all these installations. It means that if you want to use all the features of docklings, then all the features of unstructured.
Krish NAik: So, if you are doing unstructured all docs.
Krish NAik: In those cases, like, all these dependencies are required.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, as you can see, the list of all the packages, okay, and finally I'm clearing out the catcher, that's why R and iPhone F, finally. So in that way, the image becomes much more lighter.
Krish NAik: Okay? And finally, lambdaHandler.handler. Through this, I'll be starting my main application. Okay, so this part, I'll be discussing it tomorrow, don't worry, because again, code discussion is required about Magnum Adapter.
Krish NAik: You can do a local VIN if you want to do the testing, it's fine. Otherwise, no issues in that.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… Because right now, this is the direct Docker Lambda build that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just show you, like, how much time this build event takes. From here, you will get a rough idea that, what is the rough estimated time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think here… Just for me.
Krish NAik: This one…
Krish NAik: Let me think this is the one, build. Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here are rough estimated time you can get it, because in my case, a lot of things are catchy, it will be much faster, but in your case, test it, like, how much time it takes.
Krish NAik: Yes, it will be close to 5G.
Krish NAik: It's not insanely, like, if you don't want to use your… deferect, backend.
Krish NAik: The main issue is, just because of…
Krish NAik: docklink support, that becomes bigger. When you do the installation of poplars, these are much bigger, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: If you don't want to keep it, keep it, remove it.
Krish NAik: I will be showing you the implementations, Mohit. Why you were asking the same question again and again?
Krish NAik: In your case, just check approx how much time it's taking for the build And then let me know.
Krish NAik: Because in my case, a lot of things are captured by taking the installation. It takes time, it's not like that, it's super fast.
Krish NAik: Looker.w will just select the docker file, no Mithesh.
Krish NAik: Only the Dockerfile is different.
Krish NAik: Just change the Dockerfile name.
Krish NAik: How did you create this entire file from scratch?
Krish NAik: few things from my lambda, and then I added what are the files that are required in my case, then few optimizations with respect to UV that I have done according to the official,
Krish NAik: Docker Hub image of UV.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can. Actually, during the deployment, the build is done, but it's actually good practice, like, if you want to do it. Because, again, even locally cannot run it, but from here, you will get a rough estimation, like, how much time it's taking.
Krish NAik: No, no.
Krish NAik: Because dockling with its full everything, and unstructured with its everything, okay? Like, everything comes under that. Sentence transformers, transformers, everything.
Krish NAik: Okay, because of that, the build size of the docker is huge.
Krish NAik: You can use AI to generate the Dockerfile, yes, you can do that, but, your AI should have the context about your project, Aniroth.
Krish NAik: Like, what is the entry point of your application? Those things. What are the main important things, like, under… the entire app folder should be there. If at all… if at all the context, yes, you can use the app.
Krish NAik: Because if I show you my build time last time, okay, so I think… If I go here…
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think…
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I go here, this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so first time it took much more, because it's telling 5 minutes, 19 seconds, because a lot of things have been picked up from the catcher here also. But, estimated it was around, I think, 12…
Krish NAik: To, like, 15 minutes at least.
Krish NAik: Because so many, things are here, actually, in your main GitHub build.
Krish NAik: So, till this point, it becomes much faster, but, for this point, it actually, like, setting up your Docker build.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: And as I was working with much more so verifying the build, few things with respect to this, because I can see a lot of things have been picked up from the catching.
Krish NAik: No, build and push to ECR. This took really a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see, like, everything, all the steps that I've mentioned. So, for your local execution.
Krish NAik: So once… I think tomorrow you will be getting those logs once we start with the push, there's a lot of other things that needs to be configured.
Krish NAik: So, in my case, Tenla, you can see.
Krish NAik: It's going on and on.
Krish NAik: Let's see…
Krish NAik: Because a lot of, GPU things are here, actually. Because a lot of packages, though we don't have, like, CUDA packages, sentence transformers, okay.
Krish NAik: So, in your case, you need to make sure that every package, that you don't need all the functionalities of docklinks. So, very specifically in Docklinks, what you need. So, for example, if you're working with only PDFs.
Krish NAik: Then you can do unstructured, within the bracket PDF, you can pass it. So I know that in that case, only the PDF package will be installed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in that way, you have to do the optimization with respect to your package management.
Krish NAik: Now, as you can see, NVIDIA, CUDA, these things are getting installed. These are all, like, these come from docklings.
Krish NAik: So, the image build takes time, so you can do the testing.
Krish NAik: Because for tomorrow's discussion, I think, if you guys have done till the, like, the same build part, and then you have to tag, and you have to push it into ECR, okay, so these are a few of the things.
Krish NAik: Which needs to be done.
Krish NAik: And then comes creating the Lambda function. So this part, you can do it today or tomorrow, like, you can test it out later on after the class also. But I will be doing this, create lambda function tomorrow, because I need to discuss this, file with you, which is the Lambda handler, because here I have used Magnum.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you guys have not worked with AWS Lambda, okay, then previously, then it is necessary.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here everything, like, fast API with the Magna adapter that is required.
Krish NAik: And in this code, a lot of things are there with respect to your HTTP, like, API gateway from AWS, so that's why this was one of the routes that I was previously using. But again, right now, I'm not using them.
Krish NAik: These are creating some directories within your Lambda, so slash temp slash uploads later on. From here, I'll be pushing them to S3.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this comes your main app initialization. So that's why this file with the entry point, because from here, this is your main file that I need, and then comes your initialization services. So that's why this file I will be discussing tomorrow.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you guys can do the testing, you can test your local also, and then you can test the Lambda also. So both the things that you can test at all. Because these things will really take time.
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that you need to wait, and because of this only, I was working with AIM64 emails.
Krish NAik: Because initially, I tested with x86 and 64 architectures, the build was slow.
Krish NAik: But in ERM64, the main problem is getting that PyTorch backend with respect to… so it means that for every file extension, it becomes much harder for me.
Krish NAik: Okay, as I was using the hybrid chunker from Docklin. Because of that, it has a PyTorch bucket in it.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, these are even costlier as compared to ARM64 images, which are from AWS Gravitron.
Krish NAik: Because I think for in everybody's system, this build, if you're trying to do it locally, it will take a lot of time.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: I think I will be keeping it till this point only, so tomorrow's main discussion will be the lambdaHandler.py file. Okay, and then comes our app main.
Krish NAik: This file is important, because a lot of integrations from this file are actually from me.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why I'll be talking about this.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… But today, we are pretty much done.
Krish NAik: Not working, the Docker build requires one argument, just check Methage, because I think it should work.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: At first, you can stop it also, it's not necessary to build the image, you can…
Krish NAik: do a Ctrl-C, Ctrl-C.
Krish NAik: Okay, because the main purpose is, during GitHub Actions, the build should be done.
Krish NAik: And even it's for, Lambda 1. Locally, it won't work.
Krish NAik: For, that particular supporting and other things like that. So, you can simply do a Ctrl-C, Ctrl-C. I tell that from here you get it, like, how much time it will take for, do the build.
Krish NAik: Arun is asking, do we need to clean any AWS services to avoid AWS billing? I don't think. IAM user, you have created, till now, Lambda function, you have not created. Okay. ECR again, not to worry about that.
Krish NAik: If you have a single repo, right. So, again, not for that. So, nothing here till now that will be getting transferred. You do need to clean anything. Then again, you have to create tomorrow.
Krish NAik: Then don't waste time, that's it.
Krish NAik: Kareemitesh, check the command, where is the last dot?
Krish NAik: Check the command page. At least, guys, if you do a copy-paste, please look.
Krish NAik: Alright, any questions? Okay.
Krish NAik: Yeah, I can.
Krish NAik: Take questions now, so people, you can start raising your hand one by one, I'll be doing…
Krish NAik: It took 613, yes, 5 minutes is a rough one, because in the other case.
Krish NAik: Because I think in GitHub Actions, it will take more time. In local, it can be faster, but it will be much higher.
Krish NAik: Because, this deployment is a bit complex, a lot of verifications that I have kept it in between, if you check, because tomorrow, once we are done, before the final push, I'll be telling you about deploy.yml. In deploy.yml, what are the different steps that I have added? Because initially, I was using the QMU build for
Krish NAik: ARM64, but later on, I switched it off, and I moved to x86, that's why. If you have time, at least read the document that I've shared, the new deploy.md. That is the main purpose.
Krish NAik: Because a lot of other things that I face the issue, things are there. So from here, you will get an idea.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please look into that file spend, because he has this deployment.
Krish NAik: As I've taken Lambda, because of that, the complexity, if I've taken App Runner, not a bit, or EVS event, plastic beamstock, but the idea was to do everything serverless. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: We have taken that.
Krish NAik: Now, I will ask the team to provide the recording ASAP today, because…
Krish NAik: For anybody, like, who has missed the last two classes, or the last week classes, please go through that. It will become easier, at least, for you.
Krish NAik: Alright, people who want to drop, they can drop, otherwise you can simply raise your hand.
Krish NAik: Okay, so tomorrow, main lambda function creation.
Krish NAik: So… best, I think. Now, I will push, I think, that deployment file, I have changed few things, and few JSON files that I've added, okay? So, let me just push those things in GitHub.
Krish NAik: Policy file started, policy file…
Krish NAik: I have updated the report, now only just I have pushed all those policy files. If you are not creating, you can use them.
Krish NAik: But every time, just be sure, whenever you are executing, you have those variables, guys.
Krish NAik: All right, so I think then I will be concluding the session for today. Okay, as nobody has raised hands.
Krish NAik: So, simply, I think in my case also, it took around 815 seconds.
Krish NAik: In my system, it took more, I can see the Docker build is gone.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the image that you are building, it will be executing in a Lambda environment, okay? So, your local environment is not Lambda.
Krish NAik: Then for that, you have to do separate configurations.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think then I can conclude it today.
Krish NAik: Okay, guys, so let's meet tomorrow and continue our discussion. Yes, yes, nothing. You can do Ctrl-C, Ctrl-C. If you want to stop the build in between, Ctrl-C, Ctrl-C. In Windows, in Mac, Command-C, in Mac, also, I think Ctrl-C. Okay, so not Command-C.
Krish NAik: In every operating system, it's, controlled.
Krish NAik: just…
Krish NAik: Because building is not necessary, really. You can check out the local build part, don't do the build using the Lambda one. That's the main thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, now… so guys, tomorrow's session, finally, I think we can, complete the deployment, because we only need to create the Lambda function. Once the Lambda function is created, then for Lambda, I think a few permissions that needs to be passed.
Krish NAik: And then we can, actually invoke our functioning work.
Krish NAik: three to four main steps. So please go through the document, it will give you a lot of idea.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I didn't take that click-click-click approach. Otherwise, like, if you start asking me where to click, it becomes much harder. So I've kept much… most of the things in a documented way for your CLI. Later on, you can create a back script, and everything can be executed in one shot.
Krish NAik: So this is a much faster way at pinpoint of…
Krish NAik: Alrighty guys, so bye-bye everyone, thanks for joining. Let's meet tomorrow and continue our discussion.